music
音楽
applause
拍手
good night everybody
おやすみ皆さん
I actually took pictures of people for two weeks
実際に2週間にわたって人物の写真を撮りました
Looking forward to today too
今日も楽しみにしています
Let's see this crazy horse
このクレイジーな馬を見てみましょう
Then I turned out to be Vice President Wang
そしたら私は王副総統だった
Wang Fan is the vice president
王範は副社長です
because of going abroad
海外に行くから
so please let me take
だから私に撮らせてください
There are so many people present today
今日は本当にたくさんの人が出席しています
I believe that everyone is interested in this topic
誰もがこの話題に興味があると思います
very very looking forward to
とてもとても楽しみにしています
Then we also know that March
それから私たちはまた、3月があることを知っています
This Matsu, this incense
この媽祖、このお香
is a big event in Taiwan
台湾の一大イベントです
I am very happy to invite Professor Zhang Xiong here today.
本日は張雄教授をお招きできて大変嬉しく思います。
come talk to us
私たちに話しに来てください
Reasons for All Taiwanese Matsu Beliefs
台湾人のすべての馬祖信仰の理由
Like change, I probably know Mazu
変化のように、私はおそらく媽祖を知っています
This Mazu will nourish the home these activities
この媽祖は、これらの活動を家庭に栄養を与えるでしょう
I don't know anything about his origins
彼の出自については何も知りません
So I am very excited about today's speech
だから今日のスピーチはとても楽しみです
What about Dr. Zhang Xun, now he is
張勲博士は今どうなっているのですか？
Ethnic Researcher and Deputy Director
民族研究者兼副所長
He is from the Department of Anthropology, National Taiwan University
彼は国立台湾大学人類学部の出身です。
Bachelor and Master
学士と修士
During his bachelor's and master's
学士課程と修士課程の間
Taiwanese folk medicine
台湾の民間療法
and religion etc.
そして宗教など。
as the subject of his research
彼の研究の主題として
Then he went to Berkeley in the United States
その後、アメリカのバークレーに行きました
get a doctorate
博士号を取得する
After returning to Taiwan, he continued
台湾に戻った後も彼はこう続けた。
Focusing on folk belief and folk medicine
民間信仰と民間医学を中心に
to continue research
研究を続ける
Of course, I did a lot of field research.
もちろん、現地調査もたくさん行いました。
we can listen carefully today
今日は注意深く聞くことができます
Dr. Zhang is actually in the Department of Anthropology
張博士は実際には人類学部に所属しています
Probably anthropologists probably know him
おそらく人類学者はおそらく彼のことを知っているでしょう
Well, he is still teaching human beings at National Taiwan University and National Chengchi University.
さて、彼は今も国立台湾大学と国立政治大学で人間を教えています。
I just found out when I was talking to him
彼と話していて初めて知りました
The Department of Anthropology in Taiwan has very few students studying anthropology
台湾の人類学部には人類学を学ぶ学生がほとんどいません
Then his topic today is to talk about the end of the Ming Dynasty and the beginning of youth
そして今日の彼のテーマは明王朝の終わりと青春の始まりについて話すことです
He is based on this book called Tianfei Dangerous Road
彼は「天飛危険道」という本を基にしています。
The basis here
ここの根拠は
Then he added his own research
その後、彼は独自の研究を追加しました
Then come and tell us all these origins and more
それなら来て、これらすべての起源などを教えてください
I think I won't waste everyone's time
みんなの時間を無駄にすることはないと思う
We are looking forward to Zhang Guoshi's speech
張国石氏の講演を楽しみにしています
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you, Vice President Wang, for your introduction
王副社長、ご紹介ありがとうございます。
Thank you colleagues in the hospital
病院の同僚に感謝します
And good friends outside the hospital
そして病院の外の良い友達
And our folks and elders in the Nangang area
そして南港地域の私たちの仲間と長老たち
I feel honored to be here
ここにいられることを光栄に思います
Let me report my research over the past few years
過去数年間の私の研究について報告させてください
Vice President Wang Fansheng About a month or two ago
副総統 王範生 1～2か月ほど前
Notify me when I'm coming to give this speech
私がこのスピーチをするときに連絡してください
I prepared a few topics for him to choose
私は彼に選んでもらえるようにいくつかのトピックを用意しました
Because this is a more general topic
これはより一般的なトピックなので、
I haven't been in touch for a long time
長い間連絡を取っていませんでした
As a result, Vice President Wang Fansheng chose this topic
その結果、王範生副総統はこのテーマを選択した
I think he probably also
おそらく彼もそうだと思います
because he is more experienced
彼の方が経験豊富だから
He's served the feast of knowledge for a long time
彼は長い間知識の饗宴に仕えてきた
So he knows better
だから彼はもっとよく知っている
How can you resonate with the audience?
どうすれば聴衆の共感を得ることができるでしょうか？
Choose an appropriate topic
適切なトピックを選択してください
So I finally chose this topic
それで最終的にこのテーマを選びました
Feng Mazu
馮媽祖
Then he explained to me that it is best to start from the most basic
それから彼は、最も基本的なことから始めるのが最善だと私に説明しました。
Because Taiwan's Mazu belief we know is very prosperous
私たちが知っている台湾の媽祖信仰は非常に栄えているからです
But he wants me to start from this most basic source
しかし、彼は私にこの最も基本的な情報源から始めてほしいと望んでいます
History, development, and the transition to the present
歴史と発展、そして現在への変遷
make a report with everyone
みんなで報告書を作る
So what I'm talking about today
それで今日私が話していることは
If there are incomplete
不完全なものがある場合
Or you are in other parts of Taiwan
または、台湾の他の地域にお住まいですか
Because of the Mazu belief in the North, Central and South
北、中、南の媽祖信仰のため
may be slightly different
多少異なるかもしれません
What if something I said was incomplete?
私の言ったことが不完全だったらどうしますか？
Give me advice when we can exchange time again
もう一度時間を交換できるときにアドバイスをください
then i will sit down and talk now
それなら今から座って話します
This is what we say is the one who sealed Mazu in March
これが、媽祖が3月に封印されたと言うことです
Shawei Xiao Mazu
シャウェイ・シャオ・マズー
mean to say
言う意味
Because March is probably Mazu's birthday
3月はおそらく媽祖の誕生日だから
March 3rd
3月3日
Are you before the third day of the third lunar month?
旧暦の 3 月 3 日より前ですか?
you can go everywhere
どこにでも行くことができます
Mazu Temples around
媽祖廟周辺
you are from the north go south
あなたは北の出身です、南に行きなさい
Or people from your central part go to the south to enter the countryside
あるいは、中部の人々が南部に行って田舎に入る。
That's because the whole month of March
だって3月中ずっと
almost north and south
ほぼ北と南
The big and small ones of the Mazu Temple I went to
行った媽祖廟の大小
there are many activities
たくさんのアクティビティがあります
Then the believers also enjoy it
そうすれば信者も喜ぶよ
So in Taiwan there is such a
台湾にはこんなのがあるんだね
That is to say, Little Mazu Shawei
つまり、小媽祖沙偉です。
That is in so many Mazu temples in Taiwan
それは台湾の多くの媽祖廟にあります
probably at present
おそらく現時点では
Now I release these three temples
今私はこの 3 つの神殿を解放します
only famous
唯比較有名
What about these three temples in 2010
2010 年のこれら 3 つの寺院はどうなったでしょうか
also from our Ministry of Culture
私たちの文化省からも
It is said that this is a national level
これは全国レベルだと言われています
Intangible Cultural Heritage
無形文化遺産
So the Mazu Temple
それで媽祖廟
it's not just religion
それは単なる宗教ではありません
It has now become our Taiwan
今では私たちの台湾になりました
items of intangible cultural heritage
無形文化財の品目
look from the right
右から見る
Baishatun Matsu enters the village
白沙屯媽祖が村に入る
Does anyone know where Baishatun is?
白沙屯がどこにあるのか知っている人はいますか？
ok, this one goes first
OK、これが最初です
Yes, Miaoli Tongxiao
はい、苗栗通暁です
In the middle, Dajia Mazu enters the village
途中、大家媽祖が村に入る
This is probably on TV
これはおそらくテレビで放送されていると思います
The media knows that everyone
マスコミはみんな知ってるよ
There is this black and black person
この黒人と黒人がいます
The Beigang Chaotian Temple on the left
左側が北港朝天宮
Do you know where it is?
どこか分かりますか？
Yunlin
雲林
Beigang Chaotian Palace, these three are very famous
北港朝天宮、この3つは非常に有名です
then let me ask a little more
それからもう少し聞いてみましょう
Enter the countryside and follow around into the countryside
田舎に入り、田舎を追いかける
follow win mazu
フォローウィンマズ
What's the difference
違いは何ですか
why our culture is different
なぜ私たちの文化は違うのか
to choose these three
この3つを選ぶのは
if all the same thing
全部同じなら
why choose three
なぜ3つを選ぶのか
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
What's the difference
違いは何ですか
This is more subtle
これはもっと微妙です
This is slightly different
これは少し違います
wait a minute we will talk about
ちょっと待ってください、これから話します
If you take Baishatun as an example for offering incense
白沙屯を例に線香をあげると
His pilgrimage because he was from
彼の出身地による巡礼
he didn't make it that clear
彼はそこまではっきりとは言わなかった
He is from Beigang
彼は北港出身です
share it
共有する
So he goes to Beigang to enter Hong Kong every year
それで彼は毎年北港に行って香港に入国します
It's like saying just go
ちょうど行けと言っているようなものだ
You can say this when you go back to your mother's house
お母さんの家に帰ったらこう言えばいいよ
belongs to say
言うことに属する
That big one
あの大きなやつ
Wrap around into incense
お香に包み込む
Because he used to be before 1987
彼は1987年より前にいたから
Dajia also went to Beigang to worship
大佳さんも北港へ参拝に行った
But in 1988
しかし1988年に
He will no longer go to Beigang to enter Hong Kong
彼はもう北港に行って香港に入国するつもりはない
And what?
そして何？
In 1988 he changed to Newport
1988年にニューポートに移籍
after incense
お香の後
he added those two words
彼はその2つの言葉を付け加えた
Wrap around into incense
お香に包み込む
so you know the difference
だから違いがわかるでしょう
When he went to Beigang
北港に行ったとき
He is still the same as Bai Shatun
彼はまだ白沙屯と同じです
Jingxiang
ジンシャン
But after going to Newport
しかし、ニューポートに行った後
Beidajia added two words himself
Beidajia 自身が 2 つの単語を追加しました
called around Jingjing Township
京京鎮周辺を呼びました
around quiet words
静かな言葉の周りに
let's start with a little mention
ちょっとした言及から始めましょう
I'll talk about it later
それについては後で話します
That is to say, a relatively high-ranking god
つまり、比較的上位の神
he went to his jurisdiction
彼は管轄区域に行った
Or he went to the jurisdiction of a lower god
あるいは、彼は下位の神の管轄に行った
to patrol
パトロールする
go around quiet
静かに歩き回る
as if we now our chief
あたかも私たちが今のリーダーであるかのように
For example, the dean came to our Institute of Democracy
たとえば、学部長が私たちの民主主義研究所に来ました。
Check out that jurisdiction
その管轄を調べてください
Let's see if you are doing your research well.
研究がうまくできているかどうかを見てみましょう。
So Dajia Mazu went to Xingang
それで大家媽祖は新港へ行きました
He thinks he's better than Newport's
彼は自分がニューポートより優れていると思っている
Mazu is high
媽祖は高いです
So he went around the Newport
それで彼はニューポートの周りを歩き回った
have this meaning
この意味がある
so he is above the name
だから彼は名前の上にいます
He added those two words
彼はその2つの言葉を付け加えた
Then Beigang Chaotiangong only said that he was winning Mazu
すると北港朝天功は媽祖に勝つとだけ言った。
This is because the first two Baishatun and Dajia
これは、最初の 2 つの白沙屯と大佳のためです。
He is every year before March 23 baby
彼は毎年3月23日の前にいます、ベイビー
So set off to Beigang or Xingang every year
だから毎年北港か新港へ出発します
The time to enter the country is not certain
進鄉的時間不一定
As long as it is March of the lunar calendar
旧暦3月であれば
But come back to your own temple
でも自分の神殿に戻ってきてください
Must be before March 23
3 月 23 日より前である必要があります
so we can live
だから私たちは生きていける
It's for Mazu's birthday
媽祖の誕生日です
But because Beigang Chaotiangong was in his own
しかし、北港朝天宮は自分自身の中にあったので、
Xia District
夏区
He beat Mazu himself
彼は媽祖自身を倒した
It's him himself in this
この中にいるのは彼自身です
Within the range of Xia District
夏区の範囲内
Write to Mail Street
メールストリートに書き込む
So he didn't come to the country, so he didn't enter the country
つまり彼はその国に来なかったので、入国しなかったのです
Beigang is already
北港はもう
he is the boss
彼は上司です
He is the boss of many Mazu temples in Taiwan
彼は台湾の多くの媽祖廟のボスです
So he doesn't need to go outside to the countryside
だから彼は田舎に行く必要がない
he doesn't go either
彼も行きません
go around other borders
他の国境を巡る
he himself
彼が彼自身で
Gap is
ギャップは
They call that Ben South Port and Ben North Port
彼らはそれをベン・サウス・ポートとベン・ノース・ポートと呼んでいます
Because Beigang used to be
北港はかつてあったからです
The other side of the district was probably called Bengang in the Qing Dynasty.
この地区の反対側は清朝時代にはベンガンと呼ばれていたと考えられています。
Later, because of the flood, it was divided into two
その後、洪水により二つに分かれてしまいました
Two halves, so it is called Bennangang and Benbeigang
半分に分かれているので、本南港、本北港と呼ばれています。
ok so we
わかりました、それで私たちは
start with this
これから始めます
you know what to say
あなたは何を言うべきか知っていますか
There are many Mazu temples in Taiwan
台湾には媽祖廟がたくさんあります
And the Mazu Temple in Taiwan
そして台湾の媽祖廟
there are some disputes between
間にいくつかの論争があります
right
右
I've heard that there are some disputes
色々と争いがあると聞いた
Okay, let's start with the name of the city
さて、都市の名前から始めましょう
It is the beginning of explaining the name of Mazu
媽祖の名前の説明の始まりです
Generally we say worship Mazu
一般的に私たちは媽祖を崇拝すると言います。
But you see a lot of temples
でもお寺はたくさんあるよ
the name of the temple he wrote
彼が書いた寺院の名前
It's about Thean Hou Palace
天后宮についてです
Then you look at him
それからあなたは彼を見ます
those beautiful red lotus
あの美しい赤い蓮
or the whip
または鞭
written above
上に書いた
Our Lady of Heaven
天の聖母
And many believers
そして多くの信者が
Especially when it comes to Beigang
特に北港に関しては
he doesn't call mazu
彼はマズーとは電話しません
not called diva
歌姫とは呼ばれない
He also does not call Our Lady of Heaven
彼はまた、天国の聖母とも呼びません。
he called uncle
彼は叔父に電話した
uncle
叔父
call it a woman
それを女性と呼びます
Po he means like grandma
彼はおばあちゃんのような意味です
That girl?
その女の子？
It's rarely called like this in Taiwan.
台湾ではこのように呼ばれることはほとんどありません。
Generally speaking
一般的に言えば
we say diva
私たちは歌姫と言います
In fact, in the 23rd year of Kangxi
実は康熙23年に
Because the private man was in Kangxi for 22 years
なぜなら私人は22年間康熙にいたからです。
Conquered Taiwan
台湾を征服した
Then report to Emperor Kangxi of the Qing Dynasty
その後、清の康熙帝に報告する。
that is
あれは
Because of the goddess Li Mo Niang
女神リー・モニアンのせいで
help me get this taiwan
この台湾を手に入れるのを手伝ってください
So I hope this Emperor Kangxi
だから私は康熙帝がこのことを願っています
Feng Chi is the name of the goddess
フェンチーは女神の名前です
So Tianhou is Emperor Kangxi
つまり天后は康熙帝である
Only after the second wind is the Queen of Heaven
第二の風の後にのみ天国の女王が現れる
I didn't have this name before
以前はこの名前はありませんでした
That Mazu is a general folk name
媽祖というのは一般的な俗名である
what about my aunt
叔母さんはどうですか
She is called aunt in Meizhou Island.
彼女は梅州島ではおばさんと呼ばれています。
Mazu is called aunt
媽祖はおばさんと呼ばれています
So this is a very
これは非常に
very personal teaching
非常に個人的な教え
It is to regard Mazu as one's own relatives
媽祖を自分の親戚だと思うこと
aunt like this
こんなおばさん
what about mother
お母さんはどうですか
yes generally yes
はい、一般的にはい
Minnan, a native of Fujian
閩南（ミンナン） 福建省出身
A female name will be followed by a mother
女性の名前の後には母親がつきます
So there are names like this
こんな名前もあるんですね
You will want to say Mazu
媽祖と言いたくなるでしょう。
It doesn't matter whether this is mother or grandmother. Grandpa.
母親でも祖母でも、先祖でも先祖でも構いません。
It's the name of a goddess, isn't it?
女神の名前ですよね？
A little
少し
like
好き
Can't figure it out
理解できない
It doesn't have his name on it either.
それには彼の名前もありません。
That can't be used to call other goddess mothers
他の女神を母親と呼ぶのには使えない
Why is it called Mazu?
なぜ媽祖と呼ばれるのでしょうか？
Ever wondered
不思議に思ったことはありませんか
you hit worship mazu
あなたは礼拝媽祖を打った
How could Mazu be called this name?
媽祖はどうしてこの名前で呼ばれるのでしょうか？
ever wondered
今まで疑問に思ったことがある
because we know nothing but to say
私たちは言うことしか知らないから
Lin Moniang, her name is Mazu
リン・モニアン、彼女の名前は媽祖です。
We still have Chinese folk beliefs
中国には今でも民間信仰が残っている
many gods
たくさんの神様
We all use this relative to be called
私たちは皆、この相対的な名前を使用します。
You seem to say that the land lord calls him the lord
領主が領主と呼んでいるようですね。
And that Mr. Ping called him Mr.
そして、ピン氏は彼をミスターと呼んだ。
Then what about Beigong
じゃあ北貢はどうだろう
The Hakka people call the Duke of Earth and the Duke of Bei.
客家人は土公、北公のことを「北公」と呼びます。
Then Guanyin Bodhisattva is called Guanyin Bodhisattva in Buddhism
観音菩薩は仏教では観音菩薩と呼ばれます。
But what is it called in folk belief
しかし、民間信仰ではそれは何と呼ばれていますか
Avalokitesvara scolds
観音菩薩が叱る
Then the Buddha's four schools imitate the Buddha
そして、仏陀の四派は仏陀を模倣します。
In Buddhism, it is called the four imitation Buddhas
仏教では四大仏と呼ばれる
In folk belief it is called not to do
民間信仰では「してはいけない」とされています
The ancestor came out
先祖が出てきた
Avalokitesvara's scolding also came out
観世音菩薩のお叱りも出た
and some
いくつかの
those that
それらは
yes blue cow horse yes
はい、青い牛馬、はい
The star worshiped on the Qixi Festival on July 7th
7月7日の七夕祭りで崇められる星
Green cattle and horses
青牛馬
There's some left
いくつか残っています
Let me see if you can come up with an example
例を思いつくか見てみましょう
to make up for
補うために
Restock here
詰め替えはこちら
That's my mother-in-law
それは私の義母です
So sister also came out
それで妹も出てきた
then buddy
それから相棒
Brothers
ブラザーズ
He's not a honey boy, isn't he a ghost?
彼はハニーボーイじゃない、幽霊じゃないの？
what do you call him brother
あなたは彼を兄弟と何と呼びますか
that's brother right
それは兄弟ですよね
and some of that girl temple
そしてあの女の子の寺院の一部
That is to say, every girl who gets married dies
つまり、結婚した女の子は全員死ぬのです
if she thinks nothing
彼女が何も考えていないなら
Her temple can sometimes be called down
彼女の寺院は時々崩壊する可能性があります
It's just that she usually scolds very effectively
ただ、彼女は普段とても上手に叱るのです
also called her to scold
彼女を叱るためにも電話した
Actually she was a girl when she died
実は亡くなった時は女の子だった
but how to curse
でもどうやって呪うか
how to change scolding
叱り方を変えるには
Have you ever thought about these nouns
これらの名詞について考えたことがありますか
This is anthropologically
これは人類学的に言うと
That is to say, the gods of Taiwanese folk beliefs
つまり、台湾の民間信仰の神様です。
Because it bears the relative title of our Chinese
それは私たちの中国人の相対的なタイトルを冠しているからです
Then we know the gods of our folk beliefs
そうすれば、私たちの民間信仰の神がわかります
In addition to the natural gods such as the sun, the moon and the stars
太陽、月、星などの自然神に加えて、
Others are animal gods
他は動物の神様です
look at our fresh lake
私たちの新鮮な湖を見てください
those animal gods
あの動物の神様たち
then there are some plant gods
それから植物の神もいます
The big ball palace, the big tree palace
ビッグボールパレス、ビッグツリーパレス
There are also some artifact gods
アーティファクトの神もいます
That is to say, the door god, the god-maker
つまり、扉の神、神を作る者
this utensil god
この道具の神様
In addition, most of the gods of folk beliefs
また、民間信仰の神様の多くは、
People become gods after death, right?
人は死んだら神になるんですよね？
Since it was a human being
人間だったので
So between it and believers
したがって、それと信者の間では
is that we compare with
と比較するということです
if with christianity
キリスト教なら
Compared with Western Christianity
西洋キリスト教と比べて
Chinese folk beliefs
中国の民間信仰
Because its god is actually a human being
その神は実は人間だから
But because he is a sage
でも賢者だから
His personality is more noble
彼の性格はより高貴です
He deserves credit for national design
彼は国家設計において称賛に値する
So after his death he was
それで彼の死後、彼は
Akabe
あかべ
Jade Emperor Red Bee
翡翠皇帝レッドビー
It can also be killed by the emperor red bee
皇帝赤蜂にも殺される可能性があります
Then he became a god
それから彼は神になりました
So this kind of god, this kind of personality god
では、このような神、このような性格の神です。
It is a person who becomes a god after death
死後に神になる人です
Because he was the same as a human being during his lifetime
生前は人間と同じだったから
So when we call him
それで私たちが彼に電話するとき
respect him call him
彼を尊敬して彼に電話してください
Scolding Bo Gong Back Back Gong Back
叱るボーゴンバックバックゴンバック
with this your relatives
これであなたの親戚
It's a quasi-relative, a name like a relative.
準親戚、親戚のような名前です。
So there will be nouns like this
このような名詞が登場します
good
良い
Yes, because of Wen Zhugong
はい、文祖公のおかげです
The Xingtian Gong in Taipei worships
台北の行天功夫を崇拝する
Wu Enzu, you can also call him Duke Wenzhu
ウー・エンズ、文中公と呼ぶこともできます
So if he becomes a god, it's early
だから神になったら早いよ
You call him male because we know Lin Muliang
私たちはリン・ムリャンを知っているので、あなたは彼を男性と呼んでいます
He became a god in the Song Dynasty until now
宋の時代に神となり現在に至る
How could he not succeed after more than a thousand years
千年以上経ってもなぜ成功できなかったのか
Scolding him can't be the solution
彼を叱っても解決にはなりません
So this reflects another characteristic of folk beliefs
つまり、これは民間信仰の別の特徴を反映しています
That is, after the god dies, he continues to age
つまり、神は死んだ後も老化し続けるのです。
Walking, he became a god in the Song Dynasty
歩くと宋の時代に神になった
But as of now AD 2014
しかし、西暦2014年の現在では
Then we'll count how many years he's gone
それから彼が何年亡くなったか数えましょう
he's in heaven he's still alive
彼は天国にいる、まだ生きている
So we'll count his age
それで彼の年齢を数えてみましょう
Go on. He's probably still there.
彼はおそらくまだそこにいるでしょう。
still resting
まだ休んでいる
ok, this is hard to press
わかりました、これは押しにくいです
wow i turned it off
うわ、消しちゃった
Okay, let's talk about it, okay, I was just talking
わかった、それについて話しましょう、わかった、ちょうど話していたところです
Saying his name, why did he become Mazu?
自分の名前を言うと、なぜ媽祖になったのでしょうか？
Now let's talk about the century of his life
さて、彼の人生の世紀について話しましょう
his original name
彼の本来の名前
It's the name his parents gave him, Lin Mo
それは両親が彼に与えた名前です、リン・モー
Only two words Lin Mo
リン・モーはたった二言
Then we just mentioned that in Fujian, the southern part of Fujian
それから、先ほど福建省、福建省の南部について触れました。
you just have to be a girl
あなたはただ女の子である必要があります
Usually there will be a "Niang" on the back
通常は裏面に「ニアン」が入ります。
For example, my name is Zhang Xun
たとえば、私の名前は張勲です。
But you don't know that this Zhang Xun is a girl to a boy
しかし、あなたはこの張勲が女の子と男の子であることを知りません
So when you die or write in the genealogy
ですから、あなたが亡くなったり、家系図に書いたりするときは、
Just add the word "mother", then you know that Zhang Xun is a woman
「母親」という単語を追加するだけで、張勲が女性であることがわかります
Look at Lin Mo
リン・モーを見てください
He can be a man or a woman. This name
彼は男でも女でもいい、この名前は
you add a girl
あなたは女の子を追加します
So you say Mazu's name is Lin Mo
媽祖の名前はリン・モーだと言うのですね
Or call it Lin Mo Niang, both are right
またはリン・モーニアンと呼んでください、どちらも正しいです
We are all
私たちは皆、
Then according to the book I mentioned in the introduction
そして、冒頭で紹介した本によれば、
A monk in the late Ming Dynasty and the early Qing Dynasty
明代末期から清代初期の僧侶。
a buddhist daughter
仏教徒の娘
Her name is Zhao Sheng
彼女の名前はチャオ・シェンです
He said that the Tianfei who wrote it was in the book about Shenglu
これを書いた天飛は昇魯についての本に載っていると彼は言いました。
In fact, there are many different versions of the book about Mazu
実際、媽祖についての本にはさまざまなバージョンがあります。
different opinions
さまざまな意見
But Mazu has never been included in this official history
しかし媽祖はこの正史には一度も記載されていない
is the official history
それが正史です
All these Mazu wrote holy roads
これらすべての媽祖は聖なる道を書きました
Concubine Tian, ​​what mother passed on?
側室のティエン、母親は何を伝えましたか？
Our Lady of Heaven English Yuanliu Examination Many
聖母英語元柳試験多数
It's all folk notes
それはすべて民俗ノートです
It's all folk
それはすべて民俗です
Then if the version is different
それでバージョンが違うと
where they wrote his date of birth
彼の生年月日を書いた場所
parents' names
両親の名前
Brothers have different names
兄弟の名前は違う
That's why I said I'm going to order a copy
だから私はコピーを注文するつもりだと言いました
lest you mess up
台無しにしないように
but there are different versions
しかし、異なるバージョンがあります
If you are interested in those
それらに興味があるなら
You can also find another
別のものも見つけることができます
Well, write the Holy Road according to that concubine who made the saint
さて、聖者を作った側室に従って聖道を書きましょう
he is writing
彼は書いています
What about Lin Mo, she started from birth
リン・モーはどうですか、彼女は生まれたときから始めました
to the bright moon
月へ
full moon
満月
We know that the Chinese have the ritual of doing the full moon?
中国人には満月の儀式があることをご存知ですか？
when touched
触れたとき
never cried
決して泣かなかった
Never cried from birth to full moon
生まれてから満月まで一度も泣かなかった
That's why we call him Lingmo
それが私たちが彼をリンモと呼ぶ理由です
don't cry, don't cry
泣かないで、泣かないで
Usually babies cry when they are born
通常、赤ちゃんは生まれると泣きます
he didn't cry
他沒哭
But
しかし
After Yagoshi
矢越以降
will speak
話をします
Don't say Mazu is dumb
媽祖がバカだとは言わないでください
someone said
誰かが言いました
Mazu is dumb, I was wrong, if according to this book
媽祖はバカだ、私が間違っていた、この本によれば
He just didn't cry when he was born to one month old
生後1ヶ月の時は全く泣かなかった
not that he was dumb afterwards
彼が後に口をきけなくなったわけではない
Otherwise, how can he save people?
そうでなければ、どうやって人々を救うことができるでしょうか？
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
so
それで
This life is more unstable and more stable
この人生はより不安定でより安定しています
Then he was born in the first year of Song Taizu Jiannong
そして宋太祖建農元年に生まれた。
March 23
3月23
Fujian
福建省
Fuden
普田
death is in song taejoong
死はソン・テジュンの中にある
September 9th
9月9日
Died on Meizhou Island
梅州島で死去
according to the book
本によると
Mazu's father's name is Lin Yuan
媽祖の父親の名前はリン・ユアンです
mother surnamed wang
母親姓王
The couple had a son
夫婦には息子がいた
It's Mazu's elder brother named Hong Yi
媽祖の兄、ホンイです。
There are Mazu and five older sisters
媽祖と5人の姉がいる
But what?
でも何？
Lin Yuan's father
リン・ユアンの父親
He is this Putian
彼はこの莆田です
It is Du Xunjian in Putian, Xinhua
新華社莆田市の杜勲堅です
Be a petty officer, something like a police chief now
今すぐ警察署長のような下士官になってください
He thinks I'm middle-aged and only have one son
彼は私が中年で息子が一人しかいないと思っている
What are you doing with so many daughters?
こんなにたくさんの娘を抱えて何をしているのですか？
so many daughters are useless
役立たずの娘が多すぎる
only one son
息子は一人だけ
So what about this mother, this Wang family?
では、この母親、この王一家はどうなるのでしょうか？
still want to get pregnant
まだ妊娠したい
Let's see if I can have another son
もう一人息子ができるかどうか見てみましょう
Then this sub-dream in Guanpusa
それから、Guanpusa のこのサブ夢
after conception
受胎後
He always thought it was a man
彼はずっとそれを男だと思っていた
But then she was born Mazu
しかし、その後、彼女は媽祖として生まれました
and then it's special
そしてそれは特別です
When Mazu was born?
媽祖が生まれたのはいつですか？
what afternoon
何の午後
this small
この小さい
Great light shines brightly, and then the world is full of foreign lands
光が明るく輝く そして世界は異国で満ちる
There are many special phenomena
特殊現象が多い
So he knew this daughter was probably special.
したがって、彼はこの娘がおそらく特別であることを知っていました。
What about when Mazu was in her teens?
媽祖が10代の頃はどうだったのでしょうか？
There is a Taoist priest
道教の僧侶がいる
when passing by his house
彼の家の前を通りかかるとき
I think Mazu is a very smart girl
マズーはとても賢い女の子だと思います
I taught him some secrets
私は彼にいくつかの秘密を教えました
This is the Fulu, the painting of blessings, and the way of doing it.
祝福の絵とそのやり方のFuluです。
Then when Mazu was eight years old
そして媽祖が8歳のとき
Just into this private member of their dying family
死にゆく家族のこの個人的な一員に
read Confucian books
儒教の本を読む
So it can be said that this Mazu belief is in this book
したがって、この媽祖信仰がこの本にあると言えます。
He integrated the beliefs of our traditional Chinese Confucianism, Secularism and Taoism
彼は中国の伝統的な儒教、世俗主義、道教の信念を統合しました。
Inside, it's a foundation
内部は基礎です
That is to say
つまり
It is a basis for the belief in Mazu to be so widely approved
これが媽祖信仰が広く認められる根拠となっている
because most Chinese
なぜならほとんどの中国人は
You either believe in Confucianism or the world or the Tao
あなたは儒教か世界か道を信じているかのどちらかを信じています
so all acceptable
だからすべて受け入れられる
Mazu is acceptable
媽祖は受け入れられる
ok, what about now
さて、今はどうですか
Meizhou Island, let's take a look
梅州島、見てみましょう
This is the Meizhou Island that I have photographed in recent years
これは私が近年撮影した梅州島です
We know that during the Cultural Revolution, the CCP
私たちは、文化大革命の際に中国共産党が
Destroy all, almost all temples
すべて、ほぼすべての寺院を破壊する
If it is not destroyed, it will also be confiscated
破棄しなかった場合も没収される
It's a warehouse, an army barracks, a factory or a hospital.
それは倉庫、兵舎、工場、病院です。
Although Meizhou Island is off the mainland, it is on the sea
梅州島は大陸から離れていますが、海上にあります。
But it was also not allowed to worship at that time
しかし、当時は礼拝も禁止されていました
The whole island is occupied by the army
島全体が軍隊に占領されている
So now this temple hat is all see you later
さて、このテンプルハットはもう終わりです、また会いましょう
Probably only this part, this is the original temple
おそらくこの部分だけ、これが本来の寺院です
These are all newly built next to this
これらはすべてこの隣に新しく建てられたものです
That was around 1970
それは1970年頃のことでした
there is one
ここに一つ
The old lady of Meizhou Island
梅州島のおばあさん
she has a sense
彼女にはセンスがある
that is
あれは
She started to pray by herself
彼女は一人で祈り始めた
Later, with the consent of the garrison army
その後、守備隊の同意を得て
And it's on the mainland of Fujian
そしてここは福建省本土です
Some CCP cadres agree
中国共産党幹部の一部も同意
So slowly preserved the temple without damage
こうして寺院は損傷なくゆっくりと保存されました
It was not destroyed during the Cultural Revolution
文化大革命でも破壊されなかった
Now such a big conquest
今、このような大きな征服が行われています
Renovation and new construction
改修・新築
All Taiwanese believers donate money
台湾の信者全員が寄付をする
mobilized
動員された
So this is one of Taiwan's religions going back
つまり、これは台湾に遡る宗教の一つです
A big change for their local
地元にとって大きな変化
Okay, if you have sharper eyes
いいよ、もっと鋭い目を持っていれば
You can see the birthplace
発祥の地が見える
When we went in the early years
私たちが初期の頃に行ったとき
There is no big incense burner in front
正面に大きな香炉はありません
And the three small incense burners above
そして上の3つの小さな香炉
three legs
三個足台
this is later
これは後で
Later home
その後帰宅
It was just this big rock
まさにこの大きな岩でした
Then
それから
It is marked that Mazu is in
媽祖がいるとマークされています
Born in Meizhou Island
梅州島生まれ
But is Mazu from Meizhou Island?
しかし、媽祖は梅州島出身なのでしょうか？
It has been the study of Mazu in the mainland
本土では媽祖の研究が行われてきた
This has become a school
ここは学校になった
scholars
学者
a point of contention
論点
What is Mazu
媽祖とは
Kamata
蒲田
That is to say, in mainland China, Fujian
つまり、中国本土では福建省です。
What about people in Kamata?
蒲田的人呢
Or is he from Meizhou Island?
それとも梅州島出身ですか？
no way
とんでもない
they quarreled
彼らは喧嘩した
These scholars quarreled
これらの学者たちは口論した
no definite evidence to prove
証明できる明確な証拠がない
but
しかし
Death is death on Meizhou Island
梅州島では死は死だ
This is probably everyone's workers
これはおそらくみんなの労働者です
but raw words
でも生々しい言葉
we can only say
私たちはただ言うことができます
live in Kamata
生在蒲田
Because Meizhou Island also belongs to Kamata County
梅州島も鎌田県に属しているため
because you see the ones in front of you
目の前にあるものを見ているから
notebook novel
ノート小説
Local rule, local death
ローカルルール、ローカルデス
It is written that it was born in this
これに生まれたと書いてあります。
Min, Fujian
福建省ミン
but not sure
でもよくわからない
So it's probably a certainty to be born here.
だからここに生まれるのは間違いないのかもしれない。
But life is
しかし、人生というのは
born on the island
生在島上面
Or was it born on this land in Fujian?
それとも福建省のこの地で生まれたのでしょうか？
it's not sure
それは確かではありません
Then what I show you is here
それでは、私がお見せするのはここです
this
これ
photo
写真
don't know
わかりません
has anyone been there
誰かそこに行ったことがありますか
good
良い
you can say this
あなたはこれを言うことができます
next to this
この隣に
The photo didn't come out
写真が出てこなかった
old temple
古い寺院
good
良い
anyone else thought of
他の誰かが考えた
none of you went
あなたたちは誰も行きませんでした
Those who haven't raised their hands haven't been there
手を挙げていない人はそこにいません
no, not footprints
いや、足跡ではない
There's a small entrance here.
ここに小さな入り口があります。
Then here it is 10 yuan if you put it together
じゃあここでまとめると10元です
Here is a small space
ここは小さなスペースです
You can hide inside, it's that simple
中に隠れることもできる、それはとても簡単なことだ
I didn't pay attention at first
最初は気付かなかった
Later, I found out why the teacher had some female believers hiding inside.
後で、先生が女性信者を何人か潜ませていた理由が分かりました。
Later, because there was no room for two people
その後、2人で泊まれるスペースがなかったので、
so wait till the next one
だから次まで待ってて
I have a picture and someone else can come out and see it
私は写真を持っているので、他の人が出てきてそれを見ることができます
When he squeezes out like this
彼がこうやって絞り出すと
I also squeezed in to see what was inside
私も中に何が入っているのか見てみました
found that he is a small platform
彼は小さなプラットフォームであることがわかりました
Then there is a small incense burner inside
そして中には小さな香炉があります
Then I'll watch it, squeeze in and finish watching.
そしたら、ぐっと押し込んで見終わります。
i need to get out
出なければいけない
Because there will be someone waiting behind
後ろで待っている人がいるから
I just watch what they're doing
私はただ彼らがやっていることを見ているだけです
what about the women believers
女性信者はどうなるの？
What about after she got in?
彼女が入った後はどうですか？
she's over there
彼女はあそこにいる
Difficult to talk a lot
たくさん話すのは難しい
Let's talk, just talk to Mazu again
話しましょう、もう一度媽祖と話してください
So we can imagine
それで私たちは想像することができます
This should be a custom of their Meizhou Island
これは彼らの梅州島の習慣であるはずです
for example
例えば
Since Mazu ascended to heaven
媽祖が昇天してから
this place may really become a shrine
ここは本当に神社になるかもしれない
He is offering a woman believer
彼は女性信者を差し出している
A place to communicate with Mazu
媽祖との交流の場
you see you hide in
あなたが隠れているのがわかりますか
if you don't look carefully
よく見ないと
you don't notice someone is here
誰かがここにいることに気づいていない
I used to say that when I went there in 1987
1987年にそこに行ったとき、よく言っていました。
I don't have this incense burner yet
この香炉はまだ持っていません
just a big rock
ただの大きな岩
Even the red word was added later
赤い文字も後から追加されたものです
Trace it in red
赤でなぞります
So that means
つまり、
During the Cultural Revolution, no one noticed
文化大革命の時は誰も気づかなかった
There are still some religions secretly going on here
ここでは今でも密かに宗教が行われている
activities of faith
信仰的活動
So this Mazu belief is like this
さて、この媽祖信仰はこんな感じです
get down
降りる
I use this to illustrate
これを説明するために使用します
Compared with just so big, so red tail
こんなに大きいのに比べたら、こんなに赤いしっぽ
The palace here also has this small
ここの宮殿にもこんな小さなものがあります
A private place for believers to communicate with Mazu
信者が媽祖と交流できるプライベートな場所
Because of a religious belief it will be passed down
宗教的な信念があるからこそ、受け継がれていくのでしょうね
have both
両方持っています
There must be a big, public, national, official, legal, and recognized
規模が大きく、公共的で、全国的で、公的で、合法的で、認知された組織が存在する必要があります。
But there must be believers who can complain
でも文句を言える信者もいるはずだ
A place where you can communicate with the gods, both of which are indispensable
欠かせない神との交流の場
Okay, so this one is after 1987
さて、これは1987年以降のものです
We are not talking about the statue of Mazu
私たちは媽祖像のことを話しているのではありません。
Are most of them destroyed?
ほとんどが破壊されてしまったのでしょうか？
That's new
それは新しいです
This shape is from Xiamen
この形はアモイのものです
A professor at the Art Department of Xiamen University
厦門大学芸術学部教授
Called Levi's, he designed
Levi'sと呼ばれる、彼がデザインした
This Mazu looks like
この媽祖はこんな感じです
You generally have seen the statue of Mazu, right?
皆さんも媽祖像は見たことがありますよね？
What is the difference between our Mazu statues?
私たちの媽祖像の違いは何ですか?
written in Guangdong
広東省で書かれた
ok, write again
わかりました、もう一度書きます
western roots
西方的根
he did it
彼はやった
he came
彼が来た
right
右
And then there's his what
そして、そこに彼のものがあります
900,000 yuan pig
90万元の豚
usually last able to cover
通常最後にカバーできる
stay free
自由に過ごしてください
yes very good
はい。とてもいいです
This one came prepared
こちらは用意してありました
Also, and
また、そして
Listeners here, let me see
ここのリスナーの皆さん、見てみましょう
Have you seen
見たことがありますか
We are usually in Taiwan
私たちは普段台湾にいます
what you saw in the temple
神殿で見たもの
Different statues of Mazu
さまざまな媽祖像
Clam
蛤
What
何
what did the guest say
ゲストは何と言った？
girly look
ガーリーな外観
yes, his face
はい、彼の顔
not the same
同じではありません
correct
正しい
color difference
色の違い
What are most of Taiwan's Mazu
台湾の媽祖のほとんどは何ですか
black face even if not black face
黒い顔じゃなくても黒い顔
All in all a blur
全体的にぼやけてます
And even if it's not a blur
そしてたとえそれがぼやけていなくても
the hat he was also covered in
彼もかぶっていた帽子
embroidered hat
刺繍入りの帽子
And the exemption that the gentleman just said
そして紳士が今言った免除は
That's the concubine
それが側室です
The emperors who passed the tradition to China
中国に伝統を伝えた皇帝たち
he has these
彼はこれらを持っています
because all the gods form
すべての神々が形成するからです
In traditional China is the era of emperors
伝統的な中国では皇帝の時代です
This era with the imperial system of emperors
天皇制のこの時代
is regulated
規制されている
what can you take
何を持っていけますか
what are you holding
何を持っていますか
what animals can be ridden on feet
足で乗れる動物は何ですか?
and the clothes you're wearing
そしてあなたが着ている服
wear on head
頭にかぶる
there are rules
ルールがあります
It's all stipulated by Ribo
それはすべてリボによって規定されています
Equal to our current Ministry of Culture
現在の文化省に相当します
stipulated
定められた
you can't mess around
めちゃくちゃにすることはできません
If you mess around, you will be an evil god
いじると邪神になるよ
Then your temple is hidden words
そうすればあなたの神殿は隠された言葉になる
I can send the army to tear you apart
あなたを引き裂くために軍隊を送ることができます
Then his appearance is indeed similar to ours.
すると、彼の容姿は確かに私たちに似ています。
What we saw in Taiwan Mazu Temple is different
台湾媽祖廟で見たものは違う
one is color
1つは色です
Normally gods don't make white
普通神は白を作らない
white is the color of chinese party
白はチャイニーズパーティーの色です
Then why is the Mazu dancing statue in Taiwan
ではなぜ台湾の媽祖像は踊っているのでしょうか？
easy to turn black
黒くなりやすい
blackened
黒くなった
i have hinted
私は示唆しました
what i said already implied
私が言ったことはすでに暗示されています
easily blackened
黒くなりやすい
blackened why
なぜ黒くなった
Why don't you clean him up every year?
毎年彼を掃除してみませんか？
right
右
Because if Mazu's face is black,
媽祖の顔が黒ければ、
It means he's obsessed
それは彼が夢中になっていることを意味します
so many cigarettes every day blackened him
毎日たくさんのタバコで彼は黒くなった
how can i wash it off
どうすれば洗い流せますか
like there's a joke that says
というジョークがあるように
That teapot you make tea every day
あなたが毎日お茶を入れるそのティーポット
Isn't there the word tea in it?
お茶という言葉が入ってませんか？
do you want to wash him off
彼を洗い流したいですか？
Of course not
もちろん違います
The teapot is useless after washing
ティーポットは洗うと使い物にならなくなる
because of your accumulation
あなたの積み重ねのせいで
That is the historical value accumulated over the years.
それは長年にわたって蓄積された歴史的価値です。
antiques are over there
骨董品はあそこにあります
Mazu statue in Taiwan
台湾の媽祖像
You said 200 years, how do you prove it
200年って言ったけどどうやって証明するの？
If you take out a century-old Mazu
百年前の媽祖を取り出すと
No one will believe her for 200 years, right?
200年経っても誰も信じないでしょう？
Well, there is one more thing this gentleman said just now.
さて、この紳士が今言ったことがもう一つあります。
He is standing, Taiwan's Mazu
彼は立っています、台湾の媽祖
You don't stand in the temple, do you?
あなたは神殿に立っていませんよね？
Then why doesn't our Mazu stand up
ではなぜ私たちの媽祖は立ち上がらないのか
Mazu in Taiwan does not stand
台湾の媽祖は立っていない
Don't you see farther by standing?
立っていると遠くが見えませんか？
do it kindly
親切にやってください
so how
それでどうやって
to sit
座る
yes he is standing or sitting
はい、彼は立っているか座っています
It also involves where he sits, right?
それは彼が座る場所にも関係しますよね？
If you sit because there is no line below
下に列がないので座ると
is on the top of the mountain
山の頂上にあります
at the top of the mountain at the top of the mountain
山の頂上で ブラシマットの頂上で
It's weird sitting on top of a mountain, isn't it?
山の頂上に座っているのは変ですよね？
like our
私たちのように
Our Powerpoint cut off my left and right
パワーポイントが私の左右を切り取った
Just now that one is missing that, now this one is missing this
今、あれが欠けている、今、これが欠けている
The statue of Mazu is over here
媽祖像はここにあります
It is the highest point in the entire Meizhou Island
梅州島全体で最も高い場所です。
The highest point on the island stands here
島の最高点はここにあります
as a landmark
目印として
as their landmark
彼らのランドマークとして
Because even if the CCP does not ban Mazu belief now
なぜなら、たとえ中国共産党が今すぐ媽祖信仰を禁止しなくても
but it does not endorse popular belief
しかし、それは一般的な信念を支持するものではありません
You know its religious policy is
ご存じのとおり、その宗教政策は
only legal five religions
合法な宗教は5つだけ
Folk beliefs are not legal religion
民間信仰は法定宗教ではない
But in Fujian it is to open the heart
しかし福建省では心を開くことです
Welcome the return of Taiwan compatriots
台湾同胞の帰還を歓迎します
It barely makes the Mazu belief in folk belief
かろうじて媽祖信仰を民間信仰にしている
Just fight with one eye and close one eye
ただ片目で戦って片目を閉じるだけ
otherwise
さもないと
It could be Mazu belief in mainland China
中国本土の媽祖信仰かもしれない
Comparing is considered a cultural practice
比較することは文化的慣習とみなされます
So as a landmark, the shape just now serves as a landmark
だから目印として、今の形が目印になる
that i said
私が言ったこと
The design by Professor Li Weishi from the Art Department of Xiamen University
厦門大学美術学部のLi Weishi教授のデザイン
another one
もう一つ
you both mentioned
あなたたちは両方とも言いました
He is carved in white granite
彼は白い花崗岩に彫られています
Generally, our Mazu beliefs do not use stones to carve
一般に、私たちの媽祖信仰では石を使って彫刻をすることはありません。
don't use stone to carve
石を使って彫らないでください
Stone to carve can Buddha Bodhisattva in Buddhism
仏教における仏陀菩薩を彫る石
Gods not in Taoism
道教にはない神
Taoism
道教
We know that the gods of Taoism should be consecrated
私たちは道教の神々が神聖化されるべきであることを知っています
Consecrate the inside of that idol
その偶像の内側を聖別せよ
to put five treasures
宝物を５つ入れる
Right, the statue is on the back of the statue
そう、像は像の裏側にあります
Before sealing it, you need to put five treasures
封印する前に宝物を5つ入れる必要がある
five precious gold
五つの貴重な金
The picture of Jinmu fruit, that is realized, we need to put another one
ジンムフルーツの絵、それは実現しました、別のものを置く必要があります
raw worm or bee
生の虫または蜂
This makes that god like animate
こうすることで神が動き出す
Then, believers are communicating with the idol
そして、信者はアイドルとコミュニケーションをとります
You said that you communicate with stones, what is the difference between pillars and wood
石と交信すると言いましたが、柱と木の違いは何ですか？
What is the difference between statues carved out of trees and statues carved out of stone?
木から彫られた彫像と石から彫られた彫像の違いは何ですか？
There is a difference because
違いがあるので、
It's more sensitive
より敏感です
This anthropology in this around the world
世界中のこの人類学
study of gods
神々の研究
If using stones use this
石を使用する場合はこれを使用してください
What kind of stainless steel is that? Use this
ステンレスは何ですか?これを使用してください
It means that gold and steel are not bad, it means that this Buddha
金や鉄は悪くないという意味、この仏様は
it is a long time obsessed
それは長い間夢中になっています
it is long but with
長いですが、
like communication
コミュニケーションのような
like hinduism
ヒンドゥー教のように
What you want is a sense, a sense
あなたが欲しいのはセンス、センス
The induction between believers and God is Response
信者と神との間の誘導は応答である
trees are alive
木々は生きている
alive, alive
生きている、生きている
Trees
樹木齁
With stone it won't...
石だったらそんなことないよ…
If it is a stone, it will not be blackened
石なら黒くならない
the trees will be blackened
木々は黒くなるだろう
because it will go out
出てしまうから
trees will die
木は枯れるだろう
so just that
だからそれだけで
The shape of the statue of Mazu
媽祖像の形
we just know
私たちはただ知っています
Mazu belief is now in mainland China
媽祖信仰は現在中国本土にある
regarded as a landmark
ランドマークとしてみなされる
A symbol of cultural tourism
文化観光のシンボル
anything else
他に何か
sea ​​peace goddess
海上和平女神
Mazu was in 1989
媽祖は1989年に
called by the Chinese Communist Party
中国共産党から呼び出された
sea ​​peace goddess
海上和平女神
the goal is clear
目標は明確です
To maintain peace across the Taiwan Strait
台湾海峡の平和を維持するために
standing over there
あそこに立っている
where are his eyes looking
彼の目はどこを見ていますか
I will go to...
に行きます...
go to that...
そこに行って...
look carefully below
下をよく見てください
Just looking towards Beigang
北港方面を眺めるだけ
Just looking at Taiwan
台湾を見てみると
He wants to recruit Taiwan
彼は台湾を採用したいと考えている
Recruit Taiwan compatriots
台湾同胞を募る
Wait a moment
等一下
We will finally put a POPPO inside
いよいよ中にポッポを入れていきます
The roof of Chaotian Temple in Beigang, Taiwan
台湾・北港の朝天寺の屋根
There is also a statue of Mazu that is exactly the same
全く同じ媽祖像もあります
Two statues shaking each other
互いに揺れる 2 つの彫像
ok , now let ' s talk about this
さて、それではこれについて話しましょう
Okay, then this is the Mazu who gave the loan
はい、では、この人が融資をしてくれた媽祖です。
Originally, I could only get this in Taiwan
もともと台湾でしか手に入らなかった
Just turn around, I don't know who gave me a talisman
振り返ってよ、誰が私にお守りをくれたのか分からない
Then you see what the small lettering on it says
すると、そこに書かれた小さな文字が何と書かれているかがわかります
yes , your eyes are fine
はい、目は大丈夫です
can pass that vision test
その視力検査に合格できます
Wenfeng Palace in Putian, Fujian
福建省莆田市の文峰宮
Then because of the convenience of the cross-strait connection, after going to the mainland
その後、海峡横断の利便性から、大陸に行った後、
I'll go and see
行って見ます
This is really inside Wenfeng Palace in Putian, Fujian
これは実際に福建省莆田市の文峰宮の中にあります
A statue of Mazu enshrined
媽祖像が安置されている
You can see that his appearance is also different from the current Taiwanese Mazu
見た目も現在の台湾媽祖とは違うことがわかります。
You see he is also carved in stone
彼も石に彫られているのがわかります
And then he didn't have the nine exemptions just now.
それから、先ほどの九つの免除はなかった。
Not wearing a hat either
帽子もかぶってない
This is the shape of Mrs.
これがミセスの体型です。
Mazu in Song Dynasty
宋代の媽祖
We remember that we just said that Tianhou was only conferred in the 23rd year of Kangxi
天后は康熙 23 年にのみ授与されたと先ほど述べたことを覚えています。
In the Song Dynasty, when Mazu had just passed away
宋の時代、媽祖が亡くなったばかりの頃
Didn't he accumulate his merit so quickly?
彼はすぐに功績を積み上げたのではないでしょうか？
So he was conferred the title of wife by the emperor
それで彼は皇帝から妻の称号を授与されました
So in the Song Dynasty, his shape was that of a lady
つまり、宋の時代には、彼の姿は女性のようなものでした。
ok then let's talk about it now
さて、それでは今から話しましょう
How does Mazu gradually accumulate his magical machine
媽祖はどのようにして徐々に魔法のマシンを蓄積していくのか
And slowly push his status up
そして徐々にステータスを上げていきます
His team's magical machine is based on the record of the appearance of the concubine
側室の出現記録によると、彼のグループの魔術
These 16 are from his lifetime
これら 16 枚は彼の生涯のものです
He began to show his magical power, power, and spiritual power while he was alive.
彼は生前から魔法の力、力、霊的な力を発揮し始めました。
his ability
彼の能力
Because didn’t he get some secret techniques from Taoist priests?
だって道士から秘術を教わったんじゃないの？
Then he can defend the prophet
そうすれば彼は預言者を守ることができる
So we won't talk about these one by one
いくつかあるので、一つずつ説明しません
Among them, for example, the old relative on the plane is the second one.
その中で、例えば飛行機に乗っている親戚の老人は2人目です。
Whoops
おっと
I'm so sorry
ごめんなさい
I'm not familiar with this
これには詳しくありません
The old relative on the plane is
飛行機に乗っていた親戚の老人は
The first one who was blessed by the police was the Xuan Taoist who took him to the blessing of the police.
最初に警察に祝福されたのは、彼を警察の祝福に連れて行ったスアン道士でした。
Go to the wells one by one
一つずつ井戸に行きます
See the word floating up inside
内側に浮かぶ言葉を見てください
This, this, these are the blessings, heavenly scriptures, and words drawn.
これが、これが祝福であり、経典であり、描かれた言葉です。
Then the old kiss on the plane is the girl he asked for in the past
そして、飛行機の中での昔のキスは、彼が過去に求めた女の子だった
want
欲しい
Then one day when Mazu was imitating
そしてある日、媽祖が真似をしていたとき、
His original spirit went out to sea
彼の本来の魂は海へ出た
because he heard his father and brother
父と兄の声を聞いたから
They are all in the countryside
みんな田舎にいるんだよ
not the country
国ではない
their fishing village
彼らの漁村
father and brother are fishermen
父と兄は漁師です
fishing outside
外で釣りをする
his original god out
彼の本来の神が外に出た
Seeing his father and brother is a disaster
彼の父親と兄弟を見るのは災難だ
inside the shipwreck
難破船の中
so he saved his father
それで彼は父親を救った
But there is no way to save my brother
でも兄を救う方法はない
so his brother
それで彼の兄弟
If you can't save it, you will die
守れなかったら死ぬよ
but saved his father
しかし父親を救った
And there are many stories in the myth
そして神話にはたくさんの物語があります
That Mazu can subdue these
媽祖がこれらを征服できることを
Ghost, Dragon King
幽霊、竜王
And Yan Palace is their southern Fujian
そして燕宮殿は彼らにとって福建省南部です
Poseidon
ポセイドン
was also subdued by him
彼にも鎮圧された
So actually before Mazu
実は媽祖よりも前に
There are sea gods all over China
中国全土に海の神がいる
God of water, god of river, right?
水の神様、川の神様ですよね？
God of Rain and Friends of Water
雨の神様と水の仲間たち
But Mazu subdued them one by one
しかし媽祖は彼らを一人ずつ制圧した
So get yourself up
だから起きてください
Up to now, most of us worship Matsu
これまでのところ、私たちのほとんどは松を崇拝しています
Then the two ghosts Jiaying and Jiayou
そして二人の幽霊、嘉英と嘉佑が
It's the Clairvoyant Shunfeng we worship now
それは私たちが今崇拝する千里眼の俊峰です
was also subdued by him
彼にも鎮圧された
because these two monsters
なぜならこの二匹のモンスターは
At sea is always doing bad things
海ではいつも悪いことをしている
So let the fishermen have no peace
だから漁師たちに平和を与えないでください
Also received by Matsu
マツさんからも頂きました
After speaking is after Mazu was born
話した後は媽祖が生まれた後です
There are more than thirty miracle stories
30以上の奇跡の物語があります
They are all accumulated in the Song, Yuan, Ming and Qing Dynasties.
それらはすべて宋、元、明、清の時代に蓄積されました。
different
違う
The ones above here are probably from the Song Dynasty.
ここにあるものはおそらく宋の時代のものです。
Then from here
それではここから
Nu Tao Ji Ruo this is probably the Yuan Dynasty
ヌー・タオ・ジー・ルオ、これはおそらく元の時代です
Because the Yuan Dynasty had the Grand Canal
元朝には大運河があったから
then over here you see
それからここを見てください
Taijian Zhenghe belongs to the Ming Dynasty
太江正和は明王朝に属します
then to the qing dynasty
その後清朝へ
Here, the latter three are related to Taiwan.
ここで、後の 3 つは台湾に関連しています。
Then we will talk about it later
それでは、それについては後で話します
So in that book
それでその本の中で
You can see a more detailed account of these myths
これらの神話のより詳細な説明を見ることができます
So Mazu belief will be so prosperous
媽祖信仰はこれほど栄えることになる
has its social background
社会的背景がある
The first one was Mazu in the Song Dynasty
最初は宋の媽祖でした。
We say he had some mana in life
彼は人生でいくらかのマナを持っていたと言います
So he's accumulated some miracles
それで彼は奇跡を積み重ねてきた
after he left
彼が去った後
you see him in the country
あなたは田舎で彼を見かけます
small do not say
小さいとは言わないでください
The small one is, of course, that he often has
小さいものは、もちろん、彼がよく持っているものです。
Putting down the Han disaster brought some water
漢の災害を鎮圧することで水をもたらした
large at the national level
全国レベルで大きい
You see when he sends scriptures to battle
彼が聖典を戦いに送るときを見ればわかります
He helped the army of the Song Dynasty
彼は宋の軍隊を助けました
be able to return safely or in blood
無事に、または血を流しながら戻ることができる
Then during the Yuan Dynasty we knew
そして元の時代に私たちは知っていました
The newly built Grand Canal Chaoyun will bring this south of the Yangtze River
新しく建設された朝雲大運河は、これを長江の南にもたらします。
Lost to Hebei
河北に負けた
all apparition
すべての幻影
let this morning luck
今朝の幸運を祈ります
very flat
とても平らな
arrived safely
無事に到着しました
Then when Ning Dynasty
それから寧王朝のとき
the most important is
最も重要なことは
Zhenghe's seven voyages to Nanyang
鄭和の南陽への7回の航海
The Western Ocean written here is Nanyang
ここに書かれている西洋は南陽です
All are blessed by Mazu
皆は媽祖様に祝福されています
Then it came to the Qing Dynasty
そして清朝の時代へ
the biggest thing
最大のこと
is to overcome Taiwan
台湾を克服することです
good
良い
from
から
From this road in the Song Dynasty
宋の時代のこの道から
enemy is an ambassador
敵は大使
it's time to die
死ぬ時が来た
his ship was shipwrecked
彼の船は難破した
It was Mazu who saved him
彼を救ったのは媽祖だった
Then the battle between the two armies that sent gold
そして金を送った両軍の戦い
Then to the Yuan Dynasty and so on
その後、元の時代へ。
So in what I just mentioned
それで、私が今言ったことの中で、
Zhao Sheng is the monk
趙生は僧侶です
A monk in the Qing Dynasty called Zhao Sheng
清朝の僧侶「趙生」
In the book he wrote,
彼が書いた本の中で、
can see this mazu
この媽祖が見えます
He has seen miracles
彼は奇跡を見た
so his official title
だから彼の正式な肩書は
Sealed one by one, we will show you his name later
一つ一つ封印され、名前は後ほどご紹介します
So his faith slowly spread from Putian, Fujian
そこで彼の信仰は福建省莆田からゆっくりと広がりました。
To the north, to the south, to the whole of China
北へ、南へ、中国全土へ
And because of Zheng He, he also went to Southeast Asia
そして鄭和のせいで東南アジアにも行った
The entire Mazu belief
媽祖信仰全体
Zheng He Xia Xiyang, look at the part he wrote about Zheng He
鄭和夏西陽、彼が鄭和について書いた部分を見てください。
Then this is another book, because he heard that Fei Shenglu's writing is not so detailed
それから、これは別の本です。なぜなら、彼はフェイ・シェンルーの文章がそれほど詳細ではないと聞いたからです。
I used another book's
別の本を使いました
that is
あれは
Gubu is Goufu, this talk is Goufu
グブはグフ、この話はグフ
In the first year of Yongle, Taijian Zheng and he went to Xianluo, which is now Thailand
永楽元年、鄭泰建と彼は現在のタイである仙羅に行きました。
After that, Kyoto University Shinyo
然後京大新陽
His boat was about to capsize, Zheng He just prayed silently
船が転覆しそうになったとき、鄭和はただ静かに祈った
I suddenly heard the sky and the moon floating in the sky
突然空と空に浮かぶ月の音が聞こえた
I seem to see it, I seem to see it
見えるようだ、見えるようだ
God, standing on that stern
神よ、その船尾に立っておられる
top and then immediately calm down
トップにしてすぐに落ち着く
After returning, he told the emperor
帰国後、皇帝にこう告げた。
Then the emperor asked the former officials to worship this
それから皇帝はこれを拝みに来ました
Mazu, so seven times later this Zheng and Xia Xiyang
媽祖、それで 7 回後、この鄭と夏西陽
Every time before he goes to sea, he is in that Fujian
彼は海に行く前はいつもあの福建省にいる
A port next to Fuzhou is called Changle Port
福州の隣の港は長楽港と呼ばれます
Every time he goes to sea, he first worships this Mazu
彼は海に行くたびに、まずこの媽祖を崇拝します。
Then we also know that in Southeast Asia
それから東南アジアでは
About Zhenghe's century and some place names left by him
鄭和の世紀と彼が残した地名について
a lot that equals
等しい多くの
There are also scholars in Malaysia
マレーシアにも学者がいる
Survey of Mazu Belief Block 46
媽祖信仰ブロック46の調査
Except Malaysia Indonesia Singapore Thailand
マレーシアを除く インドネシア シンガポール タイ
There is Tianfei Temple, Tianhou Temple
天飛宮、天后宮があります
It can be said that as long as this is where the Chinese go
ここが中国人の行き先である限り、
or this overseas immigrant
あるいはこの海外移民
Probably will bring Mazu
おそらく媽祖を連れてくるだろう
After being on the boat and landing safely on the shore?
ボートに乗って無事に岸に着いた後は？
Just take the little Mazu on the boat
小さな媽祖を船に乗せてください
Just build a small temple and wait until you have the ability again
小さな寺院を建てて、再び能力を得るまで待つだけです
Then slowly expand the temple
そしてゆっくりと神殿を拡張していきます
Therefore, in the study of Chinese immigrants, Chinese are overseas.
したがって、中国人移民の研究では、中国人は海外にいます。
It is said that Mazu belief or Mazu Temple
媽祖信仰、あるいは媽祖廟と言われています。
almost like a
ほとんどのように
How to say this indicator is a sign
このインジケーターがサインであると言う方法
If you see a Mazu Temple in this place
この場所に媽祖廟が見えたら
Of course you are sure there is a Chinese community here
もちろん、ここに中国人コミュニティがあることは間違いありません
It is a bit like the spread of our current Christianity
それは現在のキリスト教の広がりに似ています
where is western culture
西洋文化はどこにありますか
Its church is built wherever it is, right?
その教会はどこにでも建てられますよね？
What about before the Ming and Qing Dynasties?
明代や清代以前はどうでしょうか？
Chinese culture Han people's culture
中国文化 漢民族の文化
where to
どこへ
Where will the Mazu Temple follow?
媽祖廟はどこに続くのでしょうか？
So then I had the opportunity to go to America
それでアメリカに行く機会がありました
go somewhere else
どこか他の所へ行く
I just watched his China Town
彼のチャイナタウンを見たところです
to see his Mazu Temple
彼の媽祖廟を見るために
Guangdong in the early days
初期の広東省
Now they are all brought by Taiwanese to Matsu Temple
今ではそれらはすべて台湾人によって馬祖寺に持ち込まれています。
So you can also see different dynasties, different immigrants
したがって、さまざまな王朝、さまざまな移民も見ることができます
Wave after wave, they built different Matsu temples
波に次ぐ波で、彼らはさまざまな馬祖寺院を建てました
Okay, but in the Qing Dynasty, this private man attacked Taiwan
さて、しかし清朝、この私人は台湾を攻撃しました
Register with these three stories
この3つのストーリーに登録してください
Kangxi was a private man for 21 years and 22 years
康熙帝は21年と22年間民間人だった
Get Tianfei's help when fighting Taiwan
台湾と戦うときはティエンフェイに協力してもらいましょう
So in 22 years after he conquered the hut
それで、彼が小屋を征服してから22年後、
Immediately, political and economic surrender in Taiwan
直ちに台湾の政治的・経済的降伏
So tomorrow is over
ということで明日は終わりです
The Qing Dynasty got Taiwan
清朝が台湾を手に入れた
So we say that Taiwan is in the whole of China
だから台湾は中国全土にあると言います
There are several reasons why Mazu belief is the most popular
媽祖はいくつかの理由から最も人気のある信仰です
The first one is because you immigrated to Taiwan from Fujian
1つ目は福建省から台湾に移住したからです
You want to cross the sea, so you probably want to worship Mazu
海を渡りたいから媽祖を崇拝したいのでしょう。
Second, after you come to Taiwan
2つ目は台湾に来てから
From now on, you will first settle on this coast
これからはまずこの海岸に定住することになる
on the west coast
西海岸で
Haven't turned to the back mountain, Taitung, Hualien
裏山には向いていない、台東、花蓮
You are on this coast from south to north
あなたは南から北までこの海岸にいる
From Tainan Chiayi Changhua Lugang
台南嘉義彰化鹿港から
All the way to Guandu in Taipei
台北の官渡まで
You still rely on the sea in this coastal area
この沿岸地域では今でも海に依存しています
So you still worship Mazu
それであなたは今でも媽祖を崇拝しているのですね
Plus you look at this official
さらに、この公式を見てみると、
The official initiative
公式の取り組み
The belief in Mazu was introduced to Taiwan
媽祖信仰は台湾に伝わった
The earliest belief in our Mazu
私たちの媽祖に対する最初の信仰
came through Penghu
澎湖経由で来た
Because of course you are from mainland China
もちろんあなたは中国本土出身だから
To get to Taiwan, you have to go through Penghu first.
台湾に行くには、まず澎湖を経由しなければなりません。
So the Tianfei Palace in Penghu
澎湖の天飛宮です
Now of course it's called Thean Hou Palace
今はもちろん天后宮と呼ばれています
was the earliest in our gorges
私たちの峡谷では最も早かった
Inside the Gap of the Republic of China
中華民国の狭間で
The Tianfei Palace in Penghu is the earliest
澎湖の天飛宮が最も古い
Then there is this in the island
それから島にはこれがあります
The advertisement is now Chiayi Budai
現在の広告は嘉義布大です
There is Tianfei Palace Tianfei Palace in the south of Antai
安台の南には天飛宮があります 天飛宮
And Lulmen, Kaohsiung District, this is early
そして高雄区の鹿門、これは早いです
After the Qing Dynasty, this is probably the end of the Ming Dynasty
清王朝の次は、おそらく明王朝の終わりです。
After the invasion, all the Matsu temples I saw in Taiwan
侵略後、台湾で見たすべての馬祖寺院
More than the total number of Mazu temples in mainland China
中国本土の媽祖廟の総数よりも多い
Mazu is the patron saint of Taiwan
媽祖は台湾の守護聖人です
Then this is related to the entry of the private man into Taiwan
それから、これは民間人の台湾入国に関係します。
Because after his 22 years of class
なぜなら、22年間の授業を終えた後だからです。
Emperor Kangxi criticized his private son, saying that he was of the fourth public class
康熙帝は私人の息子が公の四階級に属していると批判した
Because of the people in front
前に人がいるから
His teacher, the private man's teacher can't beat him even if he bites
彼の先生、私立男の先生は噛んでも勝てない
Private man because he is a subordinate of Zheng Chenggong
鄭成功の部下なので私人。
But his family was killed by Zheng Chenggong
しかし、彼の家族は鄭成功によって殺されました。
so he wants revenge
だから彼は復讐したいのです
Then he knows the strategy of political success
そうすれば彼は政治的成功の戦略を知っている
And the Ministry of Defense at sea
還有海上的部防
So he can successfully defeat the government
そうすれば彼は首尾よく政府を倒すことができる
rather than politics
政治というよりも
Because it has come to his son political economy
息子の政治経済にまで及んだため
so he's proud
だから彼は誇りに思っている
But when the private man heard
しかし民間人がそれを聞いたとき、
Until Emperor Kangxi wrote about him
康熙帝が彼のことを書くまで
He can't be proud
彼は自慢できない
Hurry up and say this is the help of Mazu
急いで、これは媽祖の助けだと言いなさい
So it can be said that he is
したがって、彼はそうだと言えるでしょう
Then under the Chifeng of Emperor Kangxi
その後、康熙帝の赤鳳のもとで
Mazu was named the highest queen
媽祖は最高位の女王に選ばれた
Because Si Lang is afraid that he will be the master of his own achievements.
シランは自分の功績が自分​​の主人になってしまうことを恐れているからである。
Because you want to talk if Shiro is famous
シロが有名なら話したいから
defected to the Qing Dynasty
清朝に亡命した
If he follows the example of the dignified and proclaims himself king in Taiwan
もし彼が威厳ある者の例に倣って台湾の王を名乗れば
Kangxi is tired
康熙帝は疲れている
He wants to send another general to beat him
彼は彼を倒すために別の将軍を送るだろう
Tired
疲れた
So if Shiro wants to say
だからシロが言いたいのなら
I got help from Mazu
マズさんに助けてもらいました
Then Emperor Kangxi is a bit like this
では、康熙帝はこんな感じです。
This is one of Chinese politics and religion
これは中国の政治と宗教の一つです
often appear
頻繁に現れる
the emperor borrowed
皇帝が借りた
Chifeng is a god
チーフェンは神だ
Include this place
この場所も含めて
good
良い
and what about this place
そしてこの場所はどうですか
No matter Taiwan or Fujian or Guangdong
台湾でも福建でも広東でも関係ない
you want
あなたが欲しい
become
なる
part of chinese culture
中国文化の一部
is your local god
あなたの地元の神様ですか
accepted by the emperor
皇帝に受け入れられた
enter this
これを入力してください
The system of gods in the Central Plains
中原の神々の体系
Ministry of Rites
儀式省
inside four o'clock
4時以内に
So it's a two-way
つまり双方向です
that is
あれは
The Gods of Political Incorporation
政治的法人化の神々
It means that politics has included your place
それは政治があなたの場所を含むことを意味します
that's what it means
それが意味です
good
良い
then we will
それなら私たちはそうします
Introduce a few titles of Mazu
媽祖のタイトルをいくつか紹介
he from
彼はから
What about after Mazu died?
媽祖の死後はどうなったのでしょうか？
Slowly seal him from Song High School
ゆっくりと彼を宋高校から封印してください
because he is not
彼はそうではないから
Assist Song and Jin in the war
ソンとジンの戦争を支援する
And then you see, at first it was all just Mrs.
そしてご存知のように、最初はすべて夫人だけでした。
At this time, the lady has become a concubine
この時、夫人は側室となった
Become a concubine and then arrive at the Yuan clan
側室となり袁氏に到着
become a concubine
側室になる
Na Hongwu
ナ・ホンウ
At the time of Hongwu, the holy concubine and then
紅武の時、聖妃、そしてその後
In the 19th year of Kangxi, she was still called Tianfei
康熙19年にはまだ天飛と呼ばれていた
But in twenty-three years, because of Shi Lang's relationship
でも23年後、シーランとの関係のせいで
Become him a diva, here's a jump
彼を歌姫になろう、ここがジャンプだ
It is to jump up Mazu's godhood to the highest level
媽祖の神格を最高のレベルにまで飛躍させることです
all the goddesses all
すべての女神たちすべて
Among the gods of Han people's folk beliefs, the most abundant god is Tianhou.
漢民族の民間信仰の神の中で最も多いのが天后である。
Then the fifty-ninth year of Kangxi
そして康熙五九年。
be able to program it into four o'clock
4時位置にプログラムできる
That is, the whole of China, as long as it is the Qing Dynasty
つまり清朝に限り中国全土
China ruled by
中国が統治する
Everything is fine, as long as there are believers in the temple built in your place
あなたの代わりに建てられた神殿に信者がいる限り、すべては大丈夫です
You can watch the place and sacrifice yourself in Spring and Autumn
春と秋にはその場所を見て身を捧げることができます
can make this budget
この予算を立てることができます
Officials can compile this budget
当局はこの予算を編成できます
Then he is the last, Mazu's last title
それなら彼が最後、媽祖の最後の称号だ
That is, in pastoral care for eleven years at the same time
つまり、同時に11年間司牧的ケアを行っているということです。
How many words do you look at
あなたは何単語を見ますか
I did a good job of calculating it before I came here.
ここに来る前によく計算しました。
sixty-two characters
62文字
Then it was at this time, comrade
それから、この時だった、同志
According to the regulations of the Ministry of Rites, no more
儀式省の規定によると、これ以上は禁止されています。
No one can carry it down
誰もそれを運ぶことはできません
These are sixty-two characters
これらは 62 文字です
Right, you can add another sixty-four characters, no, no
そうです、さらに 64 文字を追加できます、いいえ、いいえ
So this is the rule of the Ministry of Rites and cannot be added.
したがって、これは儀式省の規則であり、追加することはできません。
In the future, you can say that he is great
将来、彼は素晴らしいと言えるでしょう
He still has centuries of his constant apparitions
彼は今でも何世紀にもわたって定期的に出現し続けています
But the emperor just can't add words
しかし皇帝は言葉を加えることはできない
a group of four characters a group of four characters
4 文字のグループ 4 文字のグループ
A group of four characters is
4人のキャラクターのグループは、
It's all because he has a certain apparition and contributed to the country
それは彼がある幻影を持って国に貢献したからです
A group of four characters like this
こんな感じの4人組
So this is the last one and it won't change
だからこれが最後だし、変わらないよ
I can't hold it anymore, I can't add it anymore
もう我慢できない、もう付け加えられない
Okay, myths and rituals about Mazu
さて、媽祖に関する神話と儀式
We know that there is clairvoyance
私たちは透視能力があることを知っています
Then he also subdued a lot of this fish, turtle, turtle, turtle essence
それから彼はまた、この魚、亀、亀、亀のエッセンスをたくさん抑制しました
Vincent Rescue
文生救難
Besides, in terms of his rituals
さらに、彼の儀式に関しては、
There is this incense owner
こんなお香の持ち主がいる
Owner, what I just explained
オーナーさん、今説明したことは
You now understand why gods want owners
なぜ神が所有者を望んでいるのかがわかりました
The god is not the mother of the god, why do you want the owner
神様は神様の母親じゃないのに、どうして飼い主が欲しいの？
Because the gods of the Chinese people, the gods of folk belief are the same as people
中国民族の神、民間信仰の神は人と同じだから
So although Mazu became a god
媽祖は神になったものの、
But he still has to go back to see his grandparents
しかし、彼はまだ祖父母に会いに戻らなければなりません
ancestor
祖先
So also the owner
オーナーさんもそうですよ
Then there are others, these are all about Taiwan now
それから他にもありますが、これらはすべて台湾に関するものです
Zheng Chenggong is going to court, 1661
鄭成功が法廷に出廷する、1661年
When going to Taiwan from Nan'an, Fujian, passing through Xiamen
南安、福建からアモイを経由して台湾へ行く場合
At that time, the Dutch occupied Taiwan
当時オランダは台湾を占領していた
Then he went ashore again from Lu Ermen
それから彼は再び陸二門から上陸しました。
The sea never rises and cannot enter the shore
海は決して上昇せず、岸に入ることができない
He worships this Mazu
彼はこの媽祖を崇拝している
Then after the sea buried
そして海葬後
All the ships of his army may enter the port of Lummon
彼の軍のすべての船はルモンの港に入港することができる
So then he
それで彼は
But this is all
でもこれだけです
If you go to Lu Ermen to know
魯二門に行けば知ることができる
There are two Mazu temples over there
あそこには媽祖廟が二つあります
One is called Notre Dame Temple and the other is called Tianhou Temple
1つはノートルダム寺院と呼ばれ、もう1つは天后宮と呼ばれます
The two temples quarreled about who was the best gift
2 つの寺院はどちらが最高の贈り物であるかをめぐって口論した
Mazu
媽祖
This is really the most special part of Taiwan's Mazu belief.
これが台湾の媽祖信仰の最も特別な部分です。
There are always two temples to contend for
争う神殿は常に 2 つあります
Who is he
彼は誰
That's like Dajia's mother, Chen Weiyu's mother said
それはダジアの母親、チェン・ウェイユの母親のようなものです
When he wakes up in March, it starts to rain
3月に目が覚めると雨が降り始める
It just so happens that spring sowing needs rain
たまたま、春の種まきには雨が必要です
So all the farmers welcome this Yuyu?
農家の皆さんはこのゆゆを歓迎しているんですね？
Then, like this white sand bucket that lasted all night
そして一晩中続いたこの白い砂のバケツのように
Because there was no Hilo Bridge before
以前はヒロ橋がなかったので
You really have to walk across the Zuoshui River
本当に左水川を歩いて渡らなければなりません
After the Hiro Bridge
広橋を過ぎてから
No one would be so stupid as to walk Zuoshui River
左水川を歩くほど愚かな人はいないでしょう
But it was around 2008
でもそれは2008年くらいのこと
The first one we just had
ちょうど持っていた最初のもの
What you see on Powerpoint is that
パワーポイントで見ると、
White Sand Bucket book cover
ホワイトサンドバケツブックカバー
Wait a minute, we brought a few copies and will give them to everyone
ちょっと待ってください、私たちは数部持ってきたので全員に配ります
The cover is those believers carrying the bridge
表紙は橋を運ぶ信者たち
Just walk down to Zuoshui River
左水川まで歩いてすぐ
Later, because we also had colleagues to follow
その後、フォローする同僚もいたので、
I didn't leave that time
その時は行かなかった
They said that they really fully experienced the ancestors
ご先祖様のことをしっかりと体験したとのことでした
your ancestors
あなたの先祖
The road to the countryside is hard and dangerous
田舎への道は険しくて危険です
What's more, let alone coming to Taiwan from Fujian
しかも福建省から台湾に来るのはもちろん。
how dangerous is that
それはどのくらい危険ですか
Because Zuoshui River is basically dry now.
左水川は今は基本的に干上がっているからです。
no water
水がない
but still terrible
しかしまだひどい
Even now there is no water in Sasui Creek
佐水の小川には今も水がありません
nothing to be afraid of
何も恐れることはありません
still terrible
まだひどい
Our colleague goes down
私たちの同僚が倒れる
He said
彼は言った
because of the river bed
河川敷のせいで
You walk by, of course there is sand
通り過ぎると、もちろん砂があります
until the center of the river
川の中心まで
There's mud under there
この下には泥が溜まっている
and that mud will go
そうすればその泥は消えていきます
will flow
流れます
so you put your foot down
だからあなたは足を下ろします
you don't know how deep it is
それがどれくらい深いかわかりません
And then bring a little water without being completely dry
そして、完全に乾いていない状態で少量の水を持ってきてください
your body can move
あなたの体は動くことができます
But you can't step on it
でもそれを踏むことはできない
you can't step on it
あなたはそれを踏むことはできません
so it's dangerous
だから危険だよ
What's more, when there was a lot of water
さらに、水が多かったときは、
Now because Taiwan is relatively dry
今は台湾が比較的乾燥しているので
no water
水がない
so it's scary
だから怖いです
in those days they
当時彼らは
we follow
私たちはフォローする
whether to go with everyone
みんなと一緒に行くかどうか
Or follow Baishatun
または白沙屯をフォローする
You all know that I built your soil
あなたは皆、私があなたの土壌を築いたことを知っています
If you got this
これを手に入れたら
You see, from Miaoli to Beigang
ほら、苗栗から北港まで
about three days
大概三天多
then take a day off
それから一日休みなさい
Because Mazu is going back to her mother's house
マズーがお母さんの家に帰るから
Let her reunite with her mother
彼女に母親と再会させてください
rest for a day
一日休む
then walk back
それから歩いて戻ります
It takes nine days to go back and forth from Miaoli
苗栗から往復すると9日かかる
If you start from Dajia, then eight days
大甲から始めると8日
Just walk on two legs
ただ二本足で歩くだけ
How many dangers are there in the middle
真ん中には危険がどれだけあるのか
especially during the Qing Dynasty
特に清朝時代には
every village
すべての村
you out of your
あなたはあなたの外にいます
your village your fate is in doubt
あなたの村、あなたの運命は疑わしい
Because there's a bandit, there's this bandit
山賊がいるから、この山賊がいる
What kind of aborigines made grass, all kinds
どのような原住民が草を作ったのか、あらゆる種類
So it was not so easy for them to enter the countryside before.
したがって、以前は彼らが田舎に入るのはそれほど簡単ではありませんでした。
Now it's because you're on the highway
それはあなたが高速道路にいるからです
take the highway
高速道路に乗ります
Although all of Taiwan, we say that after Shawei Xiao’s mother
台湾中、シャウエイ・シャオの母親にちなんでそう言います。
The whole highway is into the countryside
高速道路全体が田園地帯に入っている
But why doesn't Bai Sha Teng Da Jia have your name?
しかし、なぜ白沙騰大佳にあなたの名前がないのですか？
Because he still keeps walking to this day
今日も歩き続けるから
One nine days, one eight days back and forth
往復で 1 回は 9 日、1 回目は 8 日
so you can fully understand
完全に理解できるように
People at that time had no roads and no lights at night
当時の人々には道路も夜も明かりがありませんでした
You're still walking there
あなたはまだそこを歩いています
Just going to the countryside can let you
田舎に行くだけでできる
wait a minute we'll talk
ちょっと待ってください、話しますから
Let you experience the most grassroots folk life
最も草の根の民俗生活を体験してみませんか
so why now
それでなぜ今
Every year until March everyone opens again
毎年3月まで全員が再開します
Starting to revive the tradition that says go
「行け」という伝統を復活させ始める
Well, the process of coming to Taiwan is in Tianhui’s sketchbook
さて、台湾に来るまでの経緯は天恵さんのスケッチブックに
There are a few myths about
についてはいくつかの迷信がありますが、
It's all about Shiro
それはすべてシロのことです
This goes back to what we just talked about
これは先ほどの話に戻りますが、
This is the statue of Mazu worshiped in a typical Taiwanese Mazu temple
これは典型的な台湾の媽祖廟で崇拝されている媽祖像です。
right? sit down
そうでしょ？座って
He sat in that temple
彼はその神殿に座っていた
Why is his Mazu banned?
なぜ彼の媽祖は禁止されているのでしょうか？
He was named Mrs. Tianhui
彼は天恵夫人と名付けられました
It's not drinking tea with nothing to do over there.
あそこでは何もすることなくお茶を飲んでいるわけではありません。
He wants every opportunity
彼はあらゆる機会を望んでいる
Just like the view of this place in ancient times, every day is full of opportunities
いにしえのこの場所の景色のように、毎日がチャンスに満ちている
So he sat in the middle of that temple
それで彼はその神殿の真ん中に座っていました
These are little idols
これらは小さなアイドルです
If you go inside the temple and look at the big statue
お寺の中に入って大きな像を見てみると
Is it the main hall or the Dingmiao?
本殿ですか、それとも定廟ですか？
Of course it is taller.
もちろん背も高くなります。
As soon as you enter the temple, you can see how big he is
寺院に入るとすぐに彼がどれほど大きいかがわかります
he is the one
彼がその人です
It's really a day-to-day job
本当に毎日の仕事です
All believers enter through the gate of his temple
すべての信者は彼の神殿の門を通って入ってくる
was seen by him
彼に見られた
He takes care of all your problems
彼はあなたのすべての問題を解決します
This is usually smaller
通常はこれより小さいです
It's just a statue, what kind of mother
それはただの像です、どんなスタートアップママですか？
What kind of Zwirner curse
ツヴィルナーの呪いとは何ですか？
It was enshrined on the boat
船上に祀られていました
This is relatively small
これは比較的小さいです
Or someone else's
あるいは他の誰かの
I just used it to illustrate
説明するために使用しただけです
The statue of Mazu in Taiwan looks like this
台湾の媽祖像はこんな感じ
And his eyes are hanging
そして彼の目は垂れ下がっている
hang down you don't get too dirty
ぶら下がって、あまり汚れないように
believer
信徒
He hangs down like this, you see
彼はあなたに姿を見せるためにこうやって垂れ下がっています
that is
あれは
He is used to process formulas
彼は式を処理するのに慣れている
There are two forms of propagation of Mazu belief
媽祖信仰の伝播には 2 つの形態がある
The first is a spider web type
まずは蜘蛛の巣です
For example, from Meizhou
たとえば梅州から
from the Song Dynasty
宋の時代から
you can spread everywhere
どこにでも広がることができます
Quanzhou, Zhangzhou, Tianjin, Taiwan
泉州市、漳州市、天津市、台湾
Another one is vertical
もう一つは縦型です
This is radiation
これは放射線です
The other one is a vertical Xi Po shape
もう1つは縦型Xi Po形状です
For example, from the Meizhou Ancestral Temple
例えば梅州祖廟より
Then it splits into Beigang Imperial Palace
その後北港故宮に分かれる
The Beigang Imperial Palace can also be divided into Dajia and Changhua
北港故宮は大甲と彰化に分けることもできます
Then Dajia and Zhengnangong can also split their spirits to Keelung
そうすれば、大甲と正南宮も精神を分けて基隆に行くことができます
So it forms such a system
それでこのようなシステムが形成されます
It's Xi Po and Kinio's
シーポーとキニオです
Zupu like our people
Zupuは私たちの人々のように
It's your Azu, Agong, Dad
それはあなたのアズ、アゴン、お父さんです
Then you can become a Pu family like you
そうすればあなたもあなたのようなプーの家族になれるでしょう
It is also a way of spreading
それも広める手段です
precisely because of this
まさにこのため
That's why we have incense and incense
だからお線香やお線香があるのです。
Because the incense is viewed from above
お香は上から見るものなので
You go down
あなたは下がります
Fenxiang is a general term, generally speaking, Fenling
フェンシャンは一般的な用語で、一般的に言えばフェンリンです。
Because if you split your spirit, you can use the method of double body
精神を分裂させれば分身の術が使えるから
For example, carve another statue of Mazu
たとえば、別の媽祖像を彫刻する
this kind of separation
このような別れ
You can also go because you have no money
お金がないから行ってもいいよ
Carve another statue of Mazu
媽祖像をもう一つ彫る
so you take a small
だからあなたは小さなものを取ります
Small incense bag, you can donate about 100 yuan
小さなお香袋、約100元寄付できます
You can get a small incense bag
小さなお香袋がもらえます
You can take it with you, and then you go to San Francisco, USA
これを持ってアメリカのサンフランシスコに行ってください。
Immigration to Brasilia
ブラジリアへの移民
That incense bag is also called split spirit
その香袋は分霊とも呼ばれます
Therefore, splitting spirits can use the method of avatars
したがって、スピリットの分割にはアバターの方法が使用できます。
Divide the statue, you can use the way of distributing incense
像を分割して、線香を分配する方法を使用できます
Bring an incense bag, it's called split spirit
香袋を持ってきてください、それは分霊と呼ばれます
Then you wait until you settle down locally
あとは現地に落ち着くまで待ちます
You have the ability, you slowly built a temple
あなたには能力がある、ゆっくりと神殿を建てた
So you have to go back and make incense
だから戻ってお香を焚かなければならない
want to go back for incense
また線香を取りに行きたい
So it's up to you to share the fragrance
香りを共有できるかどうかはあなた次第です
divide one by one
一つずつ分ける
Like the grandparents, the fathers
祖父母や父親のように
to a son
息子に
But up you go back to the owner
でも、上がれば飼い主の元に戻ります
go back and offer incense
戻って線香をあげてください
Go back and worship your grandpa and grandpa
戻って、おじいちゃん、おばあちゃんを崇拝してください
That's it
それでおしまい
The universality of the gods of Chinese folk beliefs
中国の民間信仰における神の普遍性
He actually responds to people
彼は実際に人々に反応します
The drama of the human world
人間界のドラマ
So in response to what we just said
それで、私たちが今言ったことに応えて、
why gods have that
なぜ神はそれを持っているのか
What are you scolding, work, do
何を叱ってるの、仕事して、やって。
This is why he wants the owner
だからこそ彼は飼い主を望んでいる
Then why did Da Jia give male workers a gift?
では、なぜ大佳さんは男性労働者に贈り物をしたのでしょうか？
He said that when he went back to Beigang Imperial Palace, it was the owner, Jingxiang
北港故宮に戻ると、オーナーのジンシャンさんだったという。
Okay, so here are a few pictures I took early on.
さて、ここで私が初期に撮った写真をいくつか紹介します。
In 1986, Dajia
1986年、大佳
you see what is written here
ここに何が書いてあるかわかりますか
What about this male worker who is now in Dajia?
現在大甲にいるこの男性労働者はどうですか？
don't like me posting this photo
この写真を投稿するのが気に入らない
He said that we have long since stopped going to Beigang to enter the countryside
彼は、私たちは田舎に入るために北港に行かなくなって久しいと言いました。
We are now going to Newport to look in the mirror
私たちは今、鏡を見るためにニューポートに行きます
Why are you still posting this old photo?
なんでこんな古い写真を未だに載せるの？
But history can't be erased
でも歴史は消せない
Look here, it's written as a gift to the male worker
ここを見てください、男性労働者への贈り物と書かれています
Our Lady goes to Beigang, enters the countryside and enters the valley
聖母は北港に行き、田舎に入り、渓谷に入ります
This is the headshot
これがヘッドショットです
It's Pioneer
パイオニアです
There is still a series of teams going to the countryside
まだ地方へ行くチームが続いている
Then why do you say you want to cut it?
ではなぜ切りたいと言うのでしょうか？
is the fire owner
火の所有者です
These nouns are all said by Zheng Nangong himself.
これらの名詞はすべて鄭南宮自身が言ったものです。
not what i said
私が言ったことではありません
because of an anthropological survey
人類学調査のせいで
We just use that local term
私たちはその地元の用語を使っているだけです
That is to say, the locals, the reporters
つまり、地元の人たち、記者たち
his vocabulary
彼の語彙力
It's not what we put in academic vocabulary
それは私たちが学術用語に載せるものではありません
They said they were going to hang up
彼らは電話を切るつもりだと言いました
then go to the owner
それからオーナーのところに行きます
The owner is of course bye
オーナーはもちろんバイバイ
In that era before 1987
1987年以前のあの時代
1986 was his penultimate time
1986年は彼の最後から2番目の時期だった
He stopped going to Beigang in 1988
彼は1988年に北港に行くのをやめた
he cut the fire
彼は火を切った
I can only speak with my mouth
口でしか話せません
i didn't put a photo
写真を載せませんでした
that is
あれは
Where is the incense burner in Zheng Nangong?
鄭南宮の香炉はどこにありますか？
After being brought to Beigang, the two incense burners were put together
北港に運ばれた後、2つの香炉は一緒にされました
Then the monk will start from
それから僧侶はから始めます
Use that for the incense burner in Beigang
北港の香炉はそれを使用しています
soup sticks
スープスティック
Just shake three scoops to this
これを3スクープ振るだけです
Everyone's Incense Burner
みんなの香炉
every spoonful
スプーン一杯ごとに
What Guotai Minan
国泰美南とは
good weather
いい天気
Wishing in six places, bringing the five shares of harvest like this
六か所に願いを込めて 五株の収穫をこうしてもたらす
Then everyone quickly put away his incense burner
それからみんなは急いで香炉をしまいました
put it in a packing list he brought
彼が持ってきたパッキングリストに入れて
It's just a wooden seat and a box to put it away.
木製のシートとそれをしまうための箱だけです。
That's his whole pilgrimage
それが彼の巡礼のすべてだ
The core value of the group spent tens of millions of yuan
グループの核となる価値は数千万元を費やしました
I'm going to bring this incense back
このお香を持って帰ります
Bring back the spiritual power of incense ash and take everyone
香灰の霊力を取り戻してみんなを連れて行こう
After taking it back
持ち帰ってから
Take this incense ash from Northport
この香灰をノースポートから持ってきてください
use a smaller spoon
小さめのスプーンを使う
Put them one by one into the whole Dajia
一つ一つ大佳全体に入れていきます
There are about a dozen incense burners in Zhannan Palace
樟南宮には約十数の香炉があります
This is called cutting fire
これを切断火といいます
Then Ye Zu is Ye's
そうすれば、イェズーはイェーのものです
The meaning of the Mazu of Beigang Chaotian Palace
北港朝天宮の媽祖の意味
that this is along the way
ここは途中だということ
these are old photos
これらは古い写真です
Talk about Nenjiu coffee along the way
途中で年酒コーヒーの話をする
this nenjiu coffee
この年酒コーヒー
Nen Jiuka is the believers along the way
ネン・ジウカは途中の信者です
Just arrived in Changhua
彰化に到着しました
Then they kneel down along the way
それから彼らは途中でひざまずきます
wait for that big teacher
あの大きな先生を待ってください
just pass on them
ただ彼らを渡してください
Believers say that they can pray for peace
信者たちは平和を祈ることができると言う
like that
そのように
like x-ray
X線のような
like that now what do we say
そんな感じで今何と言おうか
like tomography
断層撮影のような
Then this clairvoyance
そうするとこの透視能力は
then he
そして、彼が
all mirror images
すべての鏡像
Consisting of small groups one by one
1人ずつの小グループで構成されます
what about each group
各グループはどうですか
all have their own characteristics
どれも独自の特徴を持っています
like this show flag team is
このショーフラッグチームのように
All made up of vowed women
全員が誓いを立てた女性で構成されている
Plus he has that T-babe
それに彼にはTベイビーがいる
It's the cycling team.
サイクリングチームです。
motorcycle team
バイクチーム
that ox cart
あの牛車
lorry truck oil cable car
トラック 石油ケーブルカー
There are various teams
色々なチームがあります
So walk for several kilometers like this
このまま数キロ歩いて
The women who made the vow
誓いを立てた女性たち
because you make a wish if you say
こう言えば願いが叶うから
Son returns from military service
息子が兵役から帰ってきた
son admitted to university
息子が大学に入学した
Or my mother-in-law recovered from illness
あるいは義母が病気から回復した
Or the harvest of my fields
あるいは私の畑の収穫物
any house is fine
どの家でもいいよ
Then say that I pay my respects to my hometown
それから故郷に敬意を表しますと言ってください
Then you will come to Jingxiang
それからJingxiangに来ます
Then this is across the Hiero Bridge
それからここはヒエロ橋を渡ったところです
Then every local
それから、地元の皆さん
the local temple will come to welcome
地元のお寺が迎えに来ます
it's a bit of a parody of that
それのちょっとしたパロディです
we handed to china times
私たちはチャイナタイムズに引き渡しました
It's the time when the emperor goes on tour in micro-clothes
天皇陛下がマイクロ服を着て巡幸される時代です
then everywhere
それからどこでも
The magistrate will come to welcome
裁判官がお出迎えに来ます
well, that's exactly
まあ、まさにその通りです
Folk belief is a copy
民間信仰はコピーです
This one from our Huang Dynasty period
これは黄王朝時代のものです
A replica of the bureaucracy
官僚制のレプリカ
Then this is Beigang
じゃあここは北港だ
Beigang
北港
I didn't bring another photo
別の写真を持ってきませんでした
This is the former Beigang and the other
これが前の北港ともう一つです
The little train in Tangchang, Taiwan
台湾・唐昌の小さな電車
one fifth
五分の一
The five-point car is a small train specially used to transport
5点式車両は、輸送に特別に使用される小型列車です。
The dry slag sugar from Tangchang
唐昌産の乾燥スラグ糖
Then to Beigang
そして北港へ
The locals they organized this Dajia
地元の人々がこの大佳を企画しました
Head Township
ヘッドタウンシップ
Teams from Two Townships and Three Townships
2 つの郡区と 3 つの郡区からのチーム
He's here to sponsor this whole race team
彼はこのレースチーム全体をスポンサーするためにここにいます
all these shows
これらすべてのショー
The performances are sponsored by Sanxiang of Touxiang
公演はTouxiangのSanxiangが主催します。
So these three relative
つまり、これら 3 つは親戚です
they have some rights
彼らにはいくつかの権利がある
For example, wait until it is equal to Grandma Zu
たとえば、ズーおばあちゃんと同じになるまで待ちます。
Well
良い
After cutting the fire, when you want to go back to Dajia?
火を止めた後、大甲に戻りたいときは？
they can plug in
彼らはプラグインすることができます
like when you celebrate new year
新年を祝うときのように
Rushing to Xingtiangong Plug Township means the same thing
行天宮プラグ郷へ急ぐことも同じことを意味する
That's also a worthwhile study
それも勉強になるよ
What is Plug Township?
プラグタウンシップとは何ですか?
Why Plug Township
なぜタウンシップをプラグインするのか
Why Gardens Need Plug Boxes
庭にプラグボックスが必要な理由
what did the plug box get
プラグボックスは何になりましたか
good
良い
Then in 1988, if you see them, they won’t go
そして1988年、見かけたら行かない
Beigang is going to Xingang Public Office to open Taiwan Mazu
北港は台湾媽祖を開くために新港公署へ行く
good
良い
So we start from that temple ranking dispute
それでは、寺院のランキング論争から始めます
We can analyze the community identity of that civil society
私たちはその市民社会のコミュニティアイデンティティを分析することができます
and historical memory
そして歴史の記憶
Let's wait and see if we have time to talk about the details
詳細については時間があればお話しましょう
These are the two temples, Xingang Beigang
これが新港北崗の２つの寺院です。
They are arguing about why Beigang chose this new port in the end
北港が最終的になぜこのニューポートを選んだのかについて彼らは議論している
good
良い
That's what I'm reporting to you
それが私があなたに報告していることです
Origin and development
起源と発展
Then there is his relationship with modern society
次に、彼と現代社会との関係についてです。
Mazu belief is one of our folk beliefs in Taiwan
媽祖信仰は台湾の民間信仰の一つです
What is very special is that he followed the changes in Taiwanese society.
非常に特徴的なのは、台湾社会の変化を追ったことだ。
And it fits well
そしてそれはよくフィットします
close he is not a dead faith
閉じる 彼は死んだ信仰ではない
He is not locked in a temple
彼は寺院に閉じ込められていません
A Faith Known Only to Believers
信者のみが知る信仰
He walked with the pulse of the entire Taiwanese society
彼は台湾社会全体の鼓動とともに歩んできた
So let's just look at these five aspects
それでは、これら 5 つの側面を見てみましょう
just in politics
政治の分野だけで
We have been since 1987
私たちは1987年から活動しています
Why did he still go to Beigang in 1987?
なぜ彼は1987年にも北港に行ったのでしょうか？
I won't go there in 1988
1988年にはそこには行かない
Because of his October 1987
彼の1987年10月のせいで
1987 happened to be
1987年は偶然にも
Do you remember Mazu
媽祖を覚えていますか
died in 987
987年に死去
so
それで
Died in AD 987
西暦987年に死去
1987 coincided with the 1000th anniversary of the birth of other languages
1987 年、たまたま他の言語の誕生 1000 周年を記念しました。
What about the Meizhou Ancestral Temple?
梅州祖廟はどうですか？
They just came to open up at the time of Deng Xiaoping
鄧小平の時代にやっとオープンになったばかりだ
So come back to Taiwan
だから台湾に戻ってきて
Ancestral Temple in Meizhou is like Mazu temples all over the world
梅州祖廟は世界中の媽祖廟のようなものです
just say love
ただ愛を言ってください
welcome
いらっしゃいませ
Come back to celebrate the 1000th anniversary of the birth of Mazu
媽祖生誕 1000 周年を祝うためにまた来ましょう
Then most of the Mazu temples in Taiwan will not be moved after receiving the love iron
そうすれば、台湾のほとんどの媽祖廟は愛鉄を受け取っても動かなくなるでしょう
hide it
隠す
only Dajia
大佳だけ
because he was
彼はそうだったから
want to string together
つなぎたい
Dajia
大佳
Local people We know that all temples in Taiwan have places
地元の人々 私たちは台湾のすべての寺院に場所があることを知っています
Favorable people are supporting
優しい人が応援してるよ
They are regardless of politics, economy and religion
政治、経済、宗教は関係ありません
are tied together
一緒に結ばれています
So what about the big guys?
それで、偉い人たちはどうですか？
They want to string together they use this
彼らはこれを使ってつなぎ合わせたいと思っています
go
行く
Meizhou Township
梅州鎮
So with this invitation letter, they held a meeting in the temple.
そこで彼らはこの招待状を持って神殿で集会を開きました。
Decided to say yes we're going to take the risk
「はい、リスクを冒すつもりです」と言うことにしました
Take the risk, but you can't just go there at that time
リスクを冒してでも、その時点でそこに行くことはできません
So they flew to Japan first
それで彼らはまず日本に飛んだ
Then
それから
Then to Shanghai From Japan to Shanghai and then to Shanghai
そして上海へ 日本から上海、そして上海へ
Meizhou
梅州
good
良い
Because at that time the two sides of the strait had not yet opened
当時はまだ海峡の両側が開いていなかったので、
So after going to Meizhou in this way
こうして梅州に行ってから
Really spent the night there back to Liang's house
私は実際にそこで一晩過ごし、梁の家に戻りました。
Everyone is terrified, those directors and supervisors of Dajiazhen Nangong
大家鎮南宮の取締役と監督者は皆怖がっています。
17 people
17名
I was terrified and wondered if I would be left there by the CCP
とても怖かったので、中国共産党によってそこに置き去りにされるかどうかわかりませんでした
What if I can't come back to Taiwan in the future?
将来台湾に戻れなくなったらどうすればいいですか？
So before going back to Taiwan
ということで、台湾に戻る前に
They hurriedly told the Legislative Yuan that Liu Songfan was still at that time
彼らは急いで立法院に、当時劉松範氏はまだいたと報告した。
when the legislator
議員のとき
Liu Songfan is from Dajia
劉松範さんは大甲出身
His younger brother is Liu Songlin
弟は劉松林。
It's a person from Mazu Temple
媽祖廟の人です
So deploy it first
したがって、最初にデプロイします
Taiwan's airport can't come and arrest us
台湾の空港は私たちを逮捕することはできません
Even he is afraid that the CCP will keep him
彼自身も中国共産党に引き留められるのではないかと恐れている
But when he returned to Taiwan, he was also afraid that the Taiwan government would arrest him
しかし、台湾に戻ったとき、台湾政府に逮捕されるのではないかという不安もあった。
Because you are fat like this, aren't you?
こんなに太っているからですよね？
So fix everything here first
まずここですべてを修正してください
I'll be back when I'm done
終わったら戻ってきます
Anyway, what happened back then
とにかく、あの時何が起こったのか
You still have newspapers when you go back
帰っても新聞はまだあるよ
no drama
ドラマはない
so
それで
That is, October 1987 at that time
つまり当時は1987年10月
Dajia sneaked away to Meizhou to enter the countryside for the first time
大佳は梅州にこっそり逃げて、初めて田舎に入った
You'll be fine when you come back
戻ってきたら元気になってるよ
Then he started promoting
それから彼はプロモーションを始めました
That is to say, I am now the leader of the Mazu Temple in Taiwan
つまり、私は今、台湾の媽祖廟の指導者です。
Why?
なぜ？
If I win back the statue of Meizhou
梅州像を取り戻したら
I know the latest
最新のことは知っています
The latest Meizhou idol in Beigang is from 200 years ago
北港の最新の梅州アイドルは200年前のもの
Now this is the latest Meizhou idol
これが最新の梅州アイドルです
most fierce
最も激しい
just won back
ちょうど取り戻した
right
右
The fiercest
最も激しい
so he said my
それで彼は私のことを言いました
My Mazu is the most respectful
私の媽祖は最も敬意を表します
all Taiwan
台湾全体
Welcome all Mazu temples in Taiwan to come to my side
台湾の媽祖廟の皆さん、私のそばに来てください。
into the countryside
田舎へ
In Beigang, you just scold Dajia and say you are Sudianwang
北港では、大佳を叱って、自分は蘇典王だと言うだけです
Sudianwang
俗典旺族
you last year
去年のあなた
not last year
去年ではない
In March of this year, you still came to my side to enter the countryside
今年の3月も君は田舎に入るために僕のそばに来てくれた
Also called my owner into the countryside
主人も田舎に呼びました
You went to Meizhou in October and came back
10月に梅州に行って戻ってきましたね
You are Sudianwang
あなたはスーディアンワンです
I'm Meizhou
私は梅州です
you are directly
あなたは直接です
Dajia wants to climb from granddaughter to daughter
ダジアさんは孫娘から娘へと成長したいと考えている
I didn’t say that because we didn’t just talk about Meizhou
梅州のことだけを話したわけではないので、そうは言いませんでした
Then Beigang and then Dajia?
それから北港、そして大佳でしょうか？
Now Dajia is going up one level
Dajia が 1 レベル上がりました
He wants to climb from the status of granddaughter to the status of daughter
孫娘の地位から娘の地位に上り詰めたい
It's like this, of course Beigang won't let it go.
こんな感じですが、もちろん北港は許しません。
Then Dajia wants to make a comeback now
それならダジアは今すぐカムバックしたいと思っています
He must. Later, Beigang told you not to come.
その後、北港はあなたに来るなと言いました。
Su Dian Wang Dajia told me that I will not go
蘇典王大佳は私に行かないと言いました
i'm your sister now i'm not yours
私は今あなたの妹です、私はあなたのものではありません
I'm not your daughter. He's not going.
私はあなたの娘ではないので、彼は行かないのです。
Okay, after two people tear their faces apart
オーケー、二人が顔を引き裂いた後
That Xingang came out to be a Japanese room boss
シンガンが和室のボスとして出てきたこと
There is only one bridge between Xingang and Beigang
新港と北港の間には橋が1本しかない
Xingang said then you don't have to move
シンガンはそう言った、だったら動く必要はないよ
Anyway, when the troops of the brigade are brought down from Dajia
とにかく、旅団の軍隊が大甲から降ろされると、
Just tilt it this way at the last point
最後の点でこのように傾けるだけです
It went to Xingang
新港に行きました
So 1988 was the second year and the Newport was ready
1988 年が 2 年目で、ニューポートの準備は整いました
Open all elementary schools and clean them
すべての小学校を開放して掃除しましょう
all toilets
すべてのトイレ
That's very busy
とても忙しいですね
in a few days you will
数日以内に
You see tens of thousands of people
何万人もの人々が見ています
In 1988, there were about 60,000 pilgrims
1988年には約6万人の巡礼者がいた
You have to prepare food and drink for 60,000 people
60,000人分の食べ物と飲み物を準備しなければなりません
It's not easy
簡単ではない
Xingang Usual
新港平常
have you ever done such a thing
そんなことをしたことがありますか
Anyway, let's go like this
とにかくこのまま行きましょう
ok
Ok
So since that year
それでその年から
Every year since 1987, everyone sees
1987 年以来、毎年誰もが見ています
Didn't he get locked up for this?
彼はそのために監禁されたのではありませんか？
So he goes back every year once a week for
それで彼は毎年、週に一度戻ってきます。
The spiritual power of the Mazu who can maintain him
彼を維持できる媽祖の霊力
That's the one that hit us in Taiwan
台湾で衝撃を受けたのはこれだ
that
それか
cross-strait policy
両岸政策
Then I want you to know about the political part behind this, because although the Kuomintang, the Democratic Progressive Party, and the Kuomintang
それから、この背後にある政治的な部分について知っていただきたいのですが、なぜなら、国民党、民進党、そして国民党ですが、
But cross-strait policy
しかし、海峡横断政策
It was indeed initially opened by religious exchanges
確かに最初は宗教交流によって開かれました
Only then did the small three links
そのとき初めて、小さな 3 つのリンクが完成しました。
Daisan Street
大三通
and other exchanges
その他の交換品
good economical
経済的に良い
I use Xingang cultural and creative industry as an example
新港の文化創造産業を例に挙げます
we know in 1994
私たちは1994年に知っています
That is, the document will propose the overall construction of the community
つまり、この文書はコミュニティの全体的な構築を提案します。
In the future, every village in Taiwan
将来の台湾のすべての村
We must develop our own industry by ourselves
私たちは自分たちの産業を自分たちで発展させなければなりません
Many industries are not well developed
多くの産業が十分に発展していない
later they trial and error
その後、彼らは試行錯誤します
Many later discovered that religion
後に多くの人がその宗教を発見しました
Especially with the temple as the center of a community
特に寺院がコミュニティの中心である場合
Can gain the trust of most villagers
ほとんどの村人の信頼を得ることができる
because you see
あなたが見るから
In a village, if I say I want to build a cemetery furnace
村で墓場炉を作りたいと言ったら
simply put
簡単に言えば
Build a burial furnace
埋葬炉を建てる
Can't cover it for several years
数年はカバーできない
Same goes for building a road why
道路を建設する場合も同様です。
Yes, no benefit
はい、メリットはありません
Different parties cannot cover
異なる政党はカバーできない
But in the end, let's go to the front of the Mazu Temple, baby
でも結局、媽祖廟の前に行きましょう、ベイビー
see if you want to cover
カバーしたいかどうかを確認してください
So in other words religion plays a role
つまり、宗教が役割を果たしているということです
interracial
異人種間の
A relatively high status of the quali group
クオリグループの中でも比較的高いステータス
So I found some places later
後で調べたら、たくさんの場所があることが分かりました
The community uses the temple as a
コミュニティは寺院を
The center of overall creation of community development
まちづくりの総合創造拠点
can do something
何かができる
Environmental friendly
環境にやさしい
Like the nuclear market in Gongliao
貢寮の核市場のようなもの
We also know that repeatedly
私たちもそれを繰り返し知っています
Covered and stopped and covered
かぶって止まってかぶせて
Then there is a temple in Gongliao
それから貢寮にはお寺があります
Jiaorenhegong Mazu Temple
焦仁和宮媽祖廟
His Mazu
彼の媽祖
later known as the anti-nuclear mother
後に反核母として知られる
Because every time they go anti-nuclear
彼らが反核になるたびに
that is
あれは
As I just said, in your community
先ほども言いましたが、あなたのコミュニティでは
Half of the people are in favor of Gai and Song
国民の半数はガイとソンを支持している
because you'll get some benefits
何らかのメリットが得られるから
Half of the people opposed to capping the market
国民の半数が市場の上限規制に反対
The two factions are at loggerheads
2つの派閥は対立している
Finally, the man and the public Mazu Temple
最後に、男と公共の媽祖廟
just carry it out for a parade
パレードのために実行するだけです
That is to say, Mazu is the mother of the sea
つまり媽祖は海の母です
It's our country goddess
我が国の女神です
We want to love our family and our country
私たちは家族と国を愛したいと思っています
love our community
私たちのコミュニティを愛してください
So it is to carry Mazu out for a parade
媽祖をパレードに連れ出すためです
Her name is Fanhe
彼女の名前はファンヘです
Well, another example would be
さて、別の例としては、
DuPont in Lukang
鹿港のデュポン
We know that DuPont is an American
私たちはデュポンがアメリカ人であることを知っています
brand factory
ブランドファクトリー
He chose Lukang to build
彼は鹿港を建設することにしました
But at that time in Lukang
しかしその時鹿港では
Everyone in Lukang is against it
鹿港のみんなが反対している
Because of their what-that-waste
彼らの無駄遣いのせいで
I'm not ready today so I can't tell you the details
今日は準備ができていないので詳細は言えませんが、
will pollute the local
地元を汚染するだろう
So they also carried out the Tianhou Palace in Lukang
そこで彼らは鹿港の天后宮も執り行いました。
That is, there are two Tianhou Temples in Lukang
つまり、鹿港には天后宮が 2 つあります。
the old one
古いもの
I also carried that mother out
私もあのお母さんを連れて行きました
then say
それから言う
To protect our country
私たちの国を守るために
So Mazu has become synonymous with native land
媽祖は故郷の代名詞となった
rural pronoun
田舎の代名詞
It is Mazu who protects us
つまり、媽祖は私たちの守護者なのです
She is our Mother Earth
彼女は私たちの母なる地球です
He is our Ocean Mother Goddess
彼は私たちの海の母なる女神です
It's like becoming a spokesman for the country
まるで国の代弁者になったような気分だ
Can represent the community as a speaking symbol
コミュニティを話すシンボルとして表現できる
words of education
教育の言葉
so many years now
もう何年も経つ
You watched the TV or media reports
テレビやメディアの報道を見ました
Every time I come to the country
その国に来るたびに
You can see the studios of literature and history around the world
世界中の文学と歴史の工房を見ることができます
And Yan Xiying, a teacher in the countryside
そして田舎の教師、ヤン・シーインさん
Zhong Primary School Teacher
鍾小学校教師
They will all choose to be a person who understands the local culture
彼らは皆、現地の文化を理解する人になることを選択します
an opportunity to participate in the country
その国に参加する機会
Then along the way, I got to know some grassroots people in the rural areas of Taiwan.
そしてその過程で、台湾の農村部に住む草の根の人々と知り合うようになりました。
items of some cultures that have disappeared
消滅したいくつかの文化の品物
In addition to talking about the bottom
底辺の話に加えて
There are also 10 or 20 master and doctoral dissertations
修士論文、博士論文が10～20件あります。
Just now we met an Englishman in the audience
たった今、聴衆の中でイギリス人に会いました
where is the female graduate student who came
来た女子大学院生はどこですか
Emily
エミリー
Emily,where are you?
エミリー、どこにいるの？
He said
彼は言った
He said he was here to write Mazu's master's thesis
彼は媽祖の修士論文を書くためにここに来たと言いました
There are three doctoral dissertations that came to Zhongyuan to ask me for help
私に助けを求めて中原に来た博士論文は 3 つあります
are all
全てです
you just know
あなたはただ知っています
The Mazu culture in Taiwan has already become an issue in international academic circles
台湾の媽祖文化はすでに国際学界で問題になっている
Because you can use it to communicate with other cultures
異文化とのコミュニケーションに使えるから
compare with
と比べて
Like the Islamic pilgrimage
イスラム教の巡礼のように
catholic pilgrimage
カトリック巡礼
Pilgrimage around the world can be used for comparison
世界中の巡礼を比較に使用できます
it's educational
それは教育的です
In addition, in terms of culture, we are cultivating
また、文化面においても、
Humanities and Intangible Cultural Heritage
人文科学と無形文化遺産
especially now in 2009
特に2009年の今
Year 2009
2009年
Originally, Taiwan wanted to bring Mazu belief to UNESCO
もともと台湾は媽祖信仰をユネスコに持ち込みたかった
Unesco to apply for world-class
ユネスコ、世界クラスの登録を申請
Intangible Cultural Heritage
無形文化遺産
But this news was known by the mainland
しかしこのニュースは本土にも知れ渡った
they did it
彼らがした
Of course they do it faster
もちろん、彼らはそれをより速く行います
They got him up in a month or so
彼らは一ヶ月ほどで彼を起こした
it exploded
爆発した
explosion explosion
爆爆爆爆
There are several people who educate people from the place of Kamata
蒲田の地から人を教育する人が何人もいる
meat industry
食肉産業
The meat industry wrote those required documents
食肉業界はそれらの必要書類を作成しました
Then those people hurried to live in Beijing
それから彼らは急いで北京に住んだ
Stay in a hotel
ホテルに泊まる
How to communicate with that central-level official
その中央レベルの役人とどのようにコミュニケーションをとるか
Must be on within a few days
数日以内にオンにする必要があります
The application documents are all written
申請書類は全て書いてあります
And because the mainland came to call
そして本土が呼びに来たので
Look at the basic information about Taiwan
台湾の基本情報を見てみる
Malaysia Singapore Hong Kong
マレーシア シンガポール 香港
Information on Mazu Temples in various places in Macau
マカオ各地の媽祖廟のご案内
He just took it
彼はただそれを受け取っただけです
Wow, he represents the Mazu temples all over the world
すごい、彼は世界中の媽祖廟の代表者だ
Year 2009
2009年
successfully applied for that world-class human
世界クラスの人材への応募に成功しました
Intangible Cultural Heritage
無形文化遺産
So now Mazu belief is in mainland China
現在、媽祖信仰は中国本土にある
In addition to saying that it is to welcome Taiwan compatriots back
台湾同胞の帰還を歓迎するためだと言うほか、
another one
もう一つ
Another nice one
もう一つ素敵なものが
The impressive title
印象的なタイトル
intangible cultural heritage
無形文化遺産
you just hold this
あなたはただこれを持ってください
this hall of fame
この殿堂
this name
この名前
What reconstruction are you applying for?
どのような再建を申請していますか？
Reconstruction, renovation, addition
改築・改修・増築
usually right
通常は正しい
The local view is fine
現地の景色はいいですね
So Taiwan is also
それで台湾も
back again
再び
From 2009 to the present also rewind
2009年から現在までも巻き戻る
Many Mazu Temples in Taiwan
台湾には媽祖廟がたくさんある
I saw that I don't want to be just a tree religion
私は単なる木の宗教にはなりたくないことが分かりました
I can also tree culture customs
樹木文化の習慣もできる
So now many Mazu temples in Taiwan have also added this item
現在、台湾の多くの媽祖廟にもこのアイテムが追加されています
It is non-household cultural heritage to apply
申請対象となるのは非家庭文化財です
So there is the 2010 we just talked about
先ほど話した 2010 年のことです
Beigang Baishatun and Dajia
北港白沙屯と大甲
Just registered with the Ministry of Culture as Taiwan's national
文化部に台湾の国民として登録されたばかりです
Non-household cultural heritage
非家庭文化遺産
Then last year and now the new year is only March
それから去年、そして今では新年はまだ3月です
Last year last year Newport Toyota Palace also applied
昨年はニューポート・トヨタ・パレスも応募
but not yet
でもまだ
So it is conceivable that many temples have to apply
したがって、多くの寺院が申請をしなければならないことが考えられます。
This is Xingang 2010
これは新港2010です
I said this Haiji
ハイジって言ったんだ
Because Mazu died on September 9th?
媽祖が9月9日に亡くなったから？
After we treat Mazu as a god in Taiwan
台湾で媽祖を神として扱った後
We don't remember his Haiji
私たちは彼のハイジを覚えていません
Because you know when you hear Haiji
ハイジを聞いたらわかるから
didn't catch you
あなたを捕まえませんでした
The bad memory says he fell into the sea and died
悪い記憶では海に落ちて死んだという
right
右
Otherwise, why Haiji?
そうでなければ、なぜハイジなのでしょうか？
If he becomes an immortal, he will go to heaven and you will pay back
彼が不滅になったら、彼は天国に行き、あなたは返済するでしょう
Haiji
ハイジ
that is not
それは違います
but
しかし
this is taiwan
ここは台湾です
Because we were in the Qing Dynasty
清朝時代だったから
Accepted Mazu is already a god
媽祖はすでに神であることを受け入れた
But in Fujian, it is especially a good port
しかし、福建省では特に良い港です
The place where Mazu was born
媽祖が生まれた場所
Didn't I just say that mainland scholars have been arguing all the time?
本土の学者たちは常に議論していると言いましたよね？
One of them is that Xianlianggang is the place where Mazu was born.
その一つは、仙梁港が媽祖の生まれた場所であるということです。
people of this faction
この派閥の人たち
It is because Xianlianggang still has the temporary ancestral hall of Mazu after all.
結局のところ、仙梁崗には媽祖の仮祖殿がまだ残っているからだ。
had his first temple
彼の最初の寺院がありました
There's a lot of him in those uniforms
あの制服を着た彼がたくさんいる
those are
それらは
that well
それはまあ
Many monuments are still there
多くの記念碑がまだ残っています
so
それで
Then they will hold this Haiji
それから彼らはこのハイジを保持します
September 9
9月9日
So when you come here to do your research
それで、あなたが研究をしにここに来るとき、
You can feel that Mazu is a person
媽祖が人間であることを感じることができます
one person
一人
he
他
A moral person, a very wise person looks like this
道徳的な人、とても賢い人はこんな感じです
you just feel that he is alone
あなたは彼が一人だと感じているだけです
Unlike the Mazu we accept in Taiwan
台湾で受け入れられている媽祖とは異なります。
It's a god, it's already a god
それは神です、それはすでに神です
But Xingang Toyota's Taiwan
しかし新港トヨタの台湾
In other words, if the mainland is going to hold a big event
つまり、本土で大きなイベントが開催される場合、
There must be Taiwanese believers to sponsor
スポンサーとなる台湾の信者がいるはずだ
This is for sure
これは確かです
Napu Tianshi Wenfeng Gonggang
ナプー・ティエンシ・ウェンフェン・ゴンガン
We are not talking about the Song Dynasty Mazu
私たちは宋代の媽祖のことを話しているのではありません。
Are you enshrined here?
ここに祀られているんですか？
You see, it is also a donation from Taiwan compatriots
ほら、これも台湾同胞からの寄付ですよ
Let the whole Wenfenggong be rebuilt again
文風宮全体をもう一度再建しましょう
Otherwise, his enclosure
そうでなければ、彼の囲い
The wooden palace that is already a three-story walled building
すでに壁に囲まれた3階建ての木造宮殿
no one dares to climb up
誰も登ろうとしない
But now you see rebuilt like this
しかし、今はこのように再構築されているのがわかります
That's why I put a piece of Hainan Island because
だから海南島の一部を入れたのは、
Hainan Island because its ass is remote
海南島はお尻が遠いから
so their thean hou palace
それで彼らのテアンハウ宮殿
There is also the word Minyue here
ここにはミンユエという言葉もあります
That is to say, there are some differences from Taiwan.
つまり、台湾とは異なる点がいくつかあります。
For example, its Minyue does not have a vent
たとえば、その Minyue には通気口がありません。
Unlike Taiwan's Minyue, who will vent
発散する台湾のミンユエとは違う
That can be compared with Thean Hou Palace
天后宮と比較できる
In addition, their folk beliefs
さらに、彼らの民間信仰は、
Although it is said that Mazu applied for it in 2009
媽祖は2009年に申請したと言われていますが、
flying material cultural heritage
飛行物体文化遺産
But in such a remote place as Hainan Island
しかし海南島のような僻地では
What to manage? Intangible cultural heritage
何を管理するのか 無形文化遺産
The builder in my place is going to come in and build a building
私の代わりに建設業者が来て建物を建てる予定です
How many billions can you earn if you get the building?
建物を手に入れたら何十億稼げるでしょうか？
Why do I still have Mazu Temple?
なぜ媽祖廟がまだあるのですか？
guess guess
推測します
We are probably the only one who can see the Thean Hou Temple
天后宮を見ることができるのはおそらく私たちだけでしょう
Everything else is guesswork.
それ以外はすべて推測です。
This is also the size of the ancient mainland
これも古代大陸と同じ大きさです
The whole face of its Mazu belief
媽祖信仰の全貌
is different very different
違う とても違う
In Meizhou Island, because of the support of Taiwanese believers
梅州島では台湾の信者の支援により
so it recovers well
それでよく回復します
but in other regions
しかし他の地域では
different situations
さまざまな状況
This is about creativity
これは創造性に関するものです
It is the current cultural and creative industry
それが現在の文化・クリエイティブ産業です
That is to say, the combination of Mazu Temple
つまり媽祖廟の組み合わせ
Cultural and creative industries are used to develop his economy
文化的および創造的な産業は彼の経済を発展させるために使用されます
Then Xingang Deputy Senior Worker's
その後、新港副上級労働者の
There is a characteristic of Mazu Temple that says their Tiger Lord
媽祖廟には虎王という特徴があります
is very famous
とても有名です
So they also did this
それで彼らもこんなことをしました
In addition, this is environmentally friendly
さらに、これは環境にも優しいです
Xingang people call the foundation to do environmental protection
新港の人々は環境保護を行う財団を呼び掛けています
planting natural rice
自然米を植える
Then green their local Xingang Hong
それから地元の新港ホンを緑化します
cultural and creative industries
文化・クリエイティブ産業
These are made of incense
これらはお香でできています
incense made
お香作り
This is the new shape
これが新しい形です
also made with incense
こちらもお香で作りました
It is to become a new product in their local area
地元の新商品となること
How many people want to buy incense now
今、お香を買いたい人は何人いますか
If you go for two hundred yuan, no one will buy it.
200元出しても誰も買わないでしょう。
Because many people don't say goodbye now
今は多くの人がさよならを言わないから
But those self-confessed masters
しかし、それらの自称マスターたちは、
And those SMEs?
そしてそれらの中小企業は？
Did you say you want him to close the door?
彼にドアを閉めてほしいって言いましたか？
Mostly closed, yes
はい、ほとんど閉まっています
or go to the mainland
あるいは本土に行くか
Or buy that Vietnamese case
あるいはベトナム製のケースを買うか
Then come to Taiwan for processing
その後台湾に来て加工します
this is the cheapest
これが一番安いです
But after all, these traditions in Taiwan
しかし結局のところ、これらの台湾の伝統は
traditional craftsmen
伝統工芸士
some things he doesn't want to give up
彼が諦めたくないものがある
improve improve
改良 改善
Then the galaxy is reshaped and then spiced
次に、銀河の形状を変更し、スパイスを加えます。
What about the volunteer process and method?
ボランティアのプロセスや方法についてはどうですか？
improve and then
改善してから
can create a new market
新しい市場を創造できる
This corresponding park
この該当公園
this place is available
この場所は利用可能です
Google it yourself
自分でググってみてください
can go to play
遊びに行くことができます
it becomes a
それは
one of those playgrounds
それらの遊び場の一つ
DIY also has
DIYもあります
That restaurant also has hotels and B&Bs
あのレストランはホテルや民宿も併設している
have everything
すべてを持っています
This is a
これは
A self-contained industry after transformation
変革後の自己完結型産業
then these what
それからこれらは何ですか
ceramics
セラミックス
Because inside our traditional temple
なぜなら私たちの伝統的な寺院の中にあるからです
The process required
必要なプロセス
Now there is also this new development
さて、こんな新たな展開もあります
This is flat creation industry
これがフラットクリエーション業界です
come out
出てくる
you come again
また来ますか
didn't you just say
今言ったじゃないですか
look far away
遠くを見る
There is a new statue of Mazu
新しい媽祖像があります
Here's the Meadows Citizen in Northport
こちらはノースポートのメドウズ シチズンです
Follow the two of Nei Zun Meizhou Island to look at each other
Nei Zun Meizhou Island の 2 人をフォローして見つめ合う
Because this statue was sent by Meizhou Island
この像は梅州島から送られたものであるため、
Then Meizhou Island Nei Zun was sent by Beigang
その後梅州島内尊が北港から派遣された。
They are relatives of Dijie
彼らはディジの親戚です
Again
また
Then this new model of Mazu
そして、この新しいモデルの媽祖
It is now used by China
現在は中国でも使われている
And focus on promoting a version of Mazu
そして媽祖のバージョンの宣伝に注力する
everywhere
どこにでも
Look at that shape
その形を見てください
Now they don't enshrine
今は祀っていない
Our traditional sitting Mazu
私たちの伝統的な座り媽祖
Black
黒
So what they worship is this
それで、彼らが崇拝しているものはこれです
This is Mazu in Macau
こちらはマカオの媽祖です
Macau returned to China in 1999
マカオは1999年に中国に返還された
Mainland?
本土？
So the mainland will send them
だから本土が彼らを送るだろう
And this is one time I went to Australia for a meeting
これは私が会議のためにオーストラリアに行ったときのことです
The local friend told me
地元の友人が教えてくれました
Over there I used to have a statue of a goddess in Chinese
あそこには中国語で書かれた女神像がありました
you go and see
あなたは行って見ます
He said he couldn't figure out what kind of idol that was.
彼はそれがどんなアイドルなのか分からなかったと言いました。
let's go see
見に行きましょう
really boss
本当に上司
OK, it's concluded because time
はい、時間なので終わります
The Study of Folk Beliefs
民間信仰の研究
what we're saying is
私たちが言っていることは
he is not a dead faith
彼は死んだ信仰ではない
Nor is it a non-us related
また、当社に関係のないものでもありません
an irrelevant belief
信念とは関係のない
he can be
彼はなれるよ
he can be society's reaction
彼は社会の反応になる可能性がある
It is a response to social and cultural changes
それは社会的および文化的変化への対応です
What about research on Mazu belief?
媽祖信仰に関する研究はどうですか？
It can be said to be a benchmark for the study of folk beliefs
民間信仰研究の指標ともいえる
because of the beliefs of other gods
他の神の信仰のせいで
hasn't happened yet
まだ起こっていない
Mazu beliefs all happened first
媽祖信仰がすべて最初に起こった
After the Matsu belief first carried out this cross-strait exchange
馬祖信仰が初めてこの海峡越え交流を行ってから
All subsequent gods have gone to mainland owners
その後の神々はすべて本土の所有者の手に渡った
Look at the Emperor Baosheng
宝生皇帝を見てください
What Guangze Zunwang Sansan King
広沢祖王三三王とは
And the emperor of Xuanyuanjiao
そして玄元教の皇帝
Emperor Xuanyuan and that Emperor Guan Sheng
宣元帝とあの関聖帝
and all the gods
そしてすべての神々
Now the plane on the two sides of the strait
今、飛行機は海峡の両側にいます
If you see the one holding that god
その神を抱く者を見たら
Don't be weird, and don't look at people, it's impolite, right?
変に思わないで、人の目も見ないで、失礼ですよね？
You knew he was going to the countryside. That's right.
彼が田舎に行くことは知っていたでしょう。
Then the airlines first forbade them to take country slaves with them
その後、航空会社はまず田舎の奴隷を連れて行くことを禁止した
Because that violates the aviation safety law
航空安全法に違反するので
But not now, so many believers want
しかし、多くの信者が望んでいるのは今ではありません。
So it's just that they have another way
つまり、彼らには別の方法があるというだけです
There is an alternative to that
それに代わるものがあります
There is still time to pass
まだ時間はあります
If you hide something inside the idol
アイドルの中に何かを隠したら
Because isn’t God wearing many layers of clothes?
だって神様は何枚も服を着ているじゃないですか。
What to put in it, when the Chinese customs refuse to give it
中国の税関で差し入れを拒否された場合、何を入れるべきか
Not even now, as long as you are a believer in Taiwan
台湾の信者である限り、今でもそうではありません。
Then you walk with that idol in your arms
そしてあなたはそのアイドルを腕に抱えて歩きます
Go through the customs all the way and go inside.
税関をずっと通って中に入ります。
Customs officers in the mainland did not dare to stop
本土の税関職員はあえて止めなかった
yes he wants to buy a place
はい、彼は場所を買いたいと思っています
Because when you get on the plane, the gods also make a position
飛行機に乗ると神様も位置を決めてくれるから
also buy a place
場所も買う
so internet safety belt
インターネット安全ベルト
yes or you will fall
はい、そうでないと落ちます
So the other gods haven't seen it yet
だから他の神々はまだ見ていない
You have already seen wave after wave on Mazu belief
あなたはすでに媽祖信仰に関する波を何度も見てきました。
It is because Mazu belief is so prosperous in Taiwan
それは台湾では媽祖信仰が盛んだからです。
He is close to our life again
彼は再び私たちの生活に近づいています
All aspects of your life will drive him
あなたの人生のあらゆる側面が彼を動かすでしょう
He's also driven by you so he responds
彼もあなたに動かされているから応えてくれるのです
Therefore, the study of Matsu belief is almost a benchmark for tomorrow's belief study
したがって、馬祖信仰の研究は、ほぼ明日の信仰研究のベンチマークとなる
The other is that our faith study is to put it back
もう一つは、私たちの信仰の学びはそれを元に戻すことです。
Looking at the context of this social life
この社会生活の文脈を見ると、
OK, I'll just report here
はい、ここで報告させていただきます
Thank you very much Dr. Zhuang for the wonderful
荘先生、素晴らしいものをありがとうございました。
In just one hour, he
たった1時間で彼は、
Tell us about the origin and development of this Matsu belief
このマツ信仰の起源と発展について教えてください。
Finally, some future
最後に、いつかの未来
That is to say, in fact, I sound like Western religious culture
つまり、実際のところ、私は西洋の宗教文化のように聞こえます
full of different
さまざまなものがいっぱい
Our Matsu is almost integrated into our current life
私たちの松は、私たちの現在の生活にほぼ溶け込んでいます
ok we can open now
わかりました、今から開けます